<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Traveling Circus of Urbanism</title>
        <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/feed.xml</link>
        <description>Urban narratives and practices, collected through travel.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 23:56:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <image>
            <title>Traveling Circus of Urbanism</title>
            <url>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/assets/sitethumbnail.jpg</url>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/feed.xml</link>
        </image>
        <category>Urbanism</category>
        <category>Cities</category>
        <category>Design</category>
        <category>Travel</category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Jane and Finch, Canada's most diverse neighborhood]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/toronto/janeandfinch</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/toronto/janeandfinch</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;Jane and Finch may not be the best-planned community. Blame the ’crats who put pen to paper back in the 60s.&quot; - <em><a href="https://nowtoronto.com/news/9-things-we-love-about-jane-finch/">ENZO DIMATTEO</a>, 9 things we love about Jane-Finch</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/janeandfinch/med/janeandfinch0.jpg"></p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jane_and_Finch#cite_note-NFB_1098_homefeeling-6">Jane and Finch</a> is a neighborhood located in the northwest end of Toronto, Ontario. The neighborhood is known as the most ethnoculturally diverse neighborhood in Canada, and it has often been stigmatized as a ghetto.<br>
A few months ago Minister Michael Tibollo visited the neighborhood and made comments which they believe &quot;perpetuate negative stereotypes about the community&quot;(see this <a href="https://toronto.citynews.ca/video/2018/07/18/jane-finch-residents-defend-neighbourhood-after-ministers-comments/">newsreport</a>).</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/janeandfinch/med/janeandfinch2.jpg"></p>
<p>I am personally interested in culturally diverse neighborhoods in cities and how many of them suffer from spatial discrimination, stereotypes, and stigmatization. I couldn't take many pictures there, but if you are an urbanist, take a moment to visit Jane and Finch - it is not the best-planned neighborhood, but it has its charm. You can take a look at the inside of Jane and Finch mall, which is very vibrant. Other visitor information can be found here <a href="http://www.jane-finch.com/">Jane-Finch.com</a>.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/janeandfinch/med/janeandfinch1.jpg"></p>
<p>Moreover, if you are serious about knowing more about this kind of diverse, multicultural communities and its challenges, I'd recommend watching a <a href="https://www.nfb.ca/film/home_feeling_struggle_for_a_community/">documentary</a> about <strong>Jane and Finch: Home Feeling: Struggle for a Community by Jennifer Hodge &amp; Roger McTair</strong>.</p>
<p>It is an urgent planning concern, too - In Toronto, there are some similar neighborhoods such as <a href="https://www.ryerson.ca/content/dam/graduate/programs/ensciman/forms/RemoAgostino_RegentParkRevitalization_EnSciMan2013.pdf">Regent Park</a>, which went through massive revitalization recently. What do these communities want and how can planners tackle the issue of spatial discrimination and stigmatization, without applying a top-down revitalization approach? Prof. Mohammed Abdul Qadeer from Queen University wrote <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Multicultural-Cities-Toronto-York-Angeles/dp/1442630140">a book</a> about Multicultural Planning. We can start visiting these neighborhoods instead of talking about them, and see the everyday life of local inhabitant.</p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/janeandfinch/med/janeandfinch0.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Inside Sidewalk Labs 307： Toronto's most famous Urban laboratory]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/toronto/sidewalktoronto</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/toronto/sidewalktoronto</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="SidewalkLab Toronto" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/sidewalktoronto/med/sidewalklab9.jpg"></p>
<p>If you are an urbanist who is especially into technologies, smart cities, and citizen participation, you probably would have heard of <a href="https://www.sidewalklabs.com/">Sidewalk Lab</a> already. This increasingly famous urban innovation hub is part of Google's parent company Alphabet, and has been working on Toronto’s Eastern Waterfront to tackle the challenges of urban growth.</p>
<p>They just launched a new experimental hub and office space that is also open to the public, so of course, I went there to take a look.</p>
<p><img alt="SidewalkLab Toronto" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/sidewalktoronto/med/sidewalklab0.jpg"><br>
<img alt="SidewalkLab Toronto" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/sidewalktoronto/med/sidewalklab2.jpg"></p>
<h3>Place to experiment, and gather feedback from local citizens</h3>
<p>307, named simply after the address of the building, used to be a parking lot and fish processing plant. The design is made by <a href="https://lebelbouliane.com/">Lebel and Bouliane</a>, and a Montréal-based interaction design studio <a href="http://www.dailytouslesjours.com/">Daily tous les jours</a> (I've been a fan of this studio for a long time!) for the identity of the space.</p>
<p><img alt="SidewalkLab Toronto" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/sidewalktoronto/med/sidewalklab1.jpg"><br>
<img alt="SidewalkLab Toronto" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/sidewalktoronto/med/sidewalklab3.jpg"></p>
<p>They explain that fundamental to their process is co-creation. It feels like this philosophy is spatially represented everywhere in 307 - there are many feedback boards and sticky notes in the space that you can leave your comments behind.</p>
<p><img alt="SidewalkLab Toronto" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/sidewalktoronto/med/sidewalklab4.jpg"><br>
<img alt="SidewalkLab Toronto" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/sidewalktoronto/med/sidewalklab5.jpg"></p>
<p>One of the staffs explained to me that they are eagerly collaborating with local organizations and citizens. Sidewalk Lab is in American tech company after all - being an &quot;outsider&quot; and non-architecture professional makes it more important to work together with local brains and make itself accessible to everyone in Toronto.</p>
<h3>Place to prototype, in collaboration with local organizations</h3>
<p><img alt="SidewalkLab Toronto" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/sidewalktoronto/med/sidewalklab6.jpg"><br>
<img alt="SidewalkLab Toronto" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/sidewalktoronto/med/sidewalklab7.jpg"></p>
<p>The first thing to notice when you walk into 307 is the Dynamic Street Prototype design by <a href="https://carloratti.com/">Carlo Ratti Associati</a> and The Plan Your Neighbourhood prototype by <a href="https://ui.kpf.com/">KPFUI</a>, which you can be part of and walk through with an iPad. There are many other models and data analyses tools that have been developed to help to tackle the local challenges of Waterfront.</p>
<p>Visitors can explore these tools and prototype exhibitions to understand various design choices and evaluate planning practices. It's definitely worth exploring these tangible prototypes to have more clear imagination about the future of waterfront and give them feedback.</p>
<p><img alt="SidewalkLab Toronto" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/sidewalktoronto/med/sidewalklab8.jpg"></p>
<p>Toronto's Waterfront is changing dynamically, as many of the major cities in the world are. There have been various development plans that include a lot of condominiums and business infrastructure, such as <a href="https://www.torontocondo4u.ca/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Sugar-Wharf-Investor-Brochure.pdf">Sugar Wharf Condos</a> that aims to attract tech/creative start-ups and incubators to the city. What is always challenging and often neglected in these developments is an ability to listen to local citizens, and carefully tackle local challenges in collaboration with various organizations from different sectors. I'm very excited to see how the future of Waterfront Toronto would look like, and what role Sidewalk Lab would play.</p>
<p>Sidewalk Toronto has various public lectures, open programs, and workshops that you can take part in. I would highly recommend to visit 307 on those occasions, or simply drop by to see what is up during opening hours.</p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/sidewalktoronto/med/sidewalklab9.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ A hidden spot for creatives: 401 Richmond]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/toronto/401richmond</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/toronto/401richmond</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<blockquote>
<p>“Old ideas can sometimes use new buildings. New ideas must use old buildings.” <em>– Jane Jacobs, The Death and Life of Great American Cities, 1961.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>I don't know how to describe the joy I felt when I found the entrance to <a href="http://www.401richmond.com/">401 Richmond Building</a> for the first time during my late afternoon walk in the Fashion district in Toronto.</p>
<p><img alt="401 Richmond Building" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/401richmond/med/richmond4.jpg"><br>
<img alt="401 Richmond Building" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/401richmond/med/richmond5.jpg"></p>
<p>With a very modest, hidden look of the entrance, 401 Richmond Building is definitely heaven for people with creative, artistic spirits. This building of 4 stories at the corner of Spadina and Richmond in the heart of the Fashion District is full of galleries, offices for small startups, studio space, and other creativity-inspiring nooks. Most importantly, it's open to the public. You can just walk in and explore the building and get the inspiration battery charged right away.</p>
<p><img alt="401 Richmond Building" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/401richmond/med/richmond10.jpg"><br>
<em>At the entrance, you can check the number of artists, designers, social innovators, and non-profit organizations at 401 Richmond</em></p>
<h2>A renovated historical warehouse</h2>
<p>According to their detailed <a href="">history description</a> on their webpage, this 200,000 square foot structure was originally the site of the Macdonald Manufacturing Company, widely known as the first and finest manufacturer of tin lithography in Canada. Opened in 1884, the factory served well for the company even during the stock market crash and following the depression years. Later in 1944, The Continental Can Company of Canada took over the company -a lot of cans were produced with the work of expert craftsmen at 401 Richmond!</p>
<p><img alt="401 Richmond Building" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/401richmond/med/richmond0.jpg"><br>
<img alt="401 Richmond Building" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/401richmond/med/richmond2.jpg"><br>
<em>Each floor has a different character, and you can find art pieces and small exhibitions on the corridors.</em></p>
<p>Shortly after the takeover though, there was a strike which eventually brought about the closure of the factory in 1967. The manufacturer moved to different locations in the suburbs, and up until 1994, the building was neglected. It was a hard time for the neighborhood itself, when most of the industry moved out to the suburbs and building vacancy increased.</p>
<p><img alt="401 Richmond Building" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/401richmond/med/richmond6.jpg"><br>
<em>There is a beautiful courtyard in the middle, and rooftop terrace on top. Thier <a href="http://www.401richmond.com/about/gardens/">gardens</a> is an oasis.</em><br>
<img alt="401 Richmond Building" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/401richmond/med/richmond7.jpg"><br>
<img alt="401 Richmond Building" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/401richmond/med/richmond8.jpg"></p>
<h2>And of course, the spirits of Jane Jacobs is here.</h2>
<p>Then what happened? A gamechanger was Margie Zeidler - who studied architecture at the University of Toronto and was influenced by our hero Jane Jacobs, an extraordinary urban thinker and visionary, during her student years. Thanks to Zeidler and people who shared the vision with her, 401 Richmond was purchased and saved from demolition.</p>
<p>One of the major obstacles for renovating old buildings is zoning. However, by 1996, parts of the prohibitive zoning restrictions were lifted, which permits some new developments and investments to happen in the area. They then gradually moved their way towards the current shape of 401 Richmond, inviting small organizations and companies with a focus on arts, culture, social innovations, and other creative initiatives. The tenants are carefully curated to create vibrant, diverse environment that fosters both business and creativity.</p>
<p><img alt="401 Richmond Building" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/401richmond/med/richmond9.jpg"></p>
<p>When you walk around 401 Richmond of today, you can feel the spirit of Jane Jacobs everywhere, in every detail. She fought for the need for diversity within a community, and places for people. What would Jane Jacobs do? is still accurate, and even urgent question to ask in our time today.</p>
<p><img alt="401 Richmond Building" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/401richmond/med/richmond1.jpg"><br>
<img alt="401 Richmond Building" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/401richmond/med/richmond11.jpg"></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/401richmond/med/richmond3.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ The urbanist's guide to Toronto]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/toronto/Introduction</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/toronto/Introduction</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/Introduction/med/toronto01.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Ali Tawfiq on Unsplash</em></p>
<h3>Places to go, projects to check out</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>The project initiatives by Waterfront Toronto and <a href="https://sidewalktoronto.ca/">Sidewalk Lab</a> is probably one of the hottest urban issues in Toronto right now. They are testing some of the Google-affiliate’s plans to develop a long list of futuristic “smart city” innovations with some new urban technologies.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.thebentway.ca/">The Bentway</a> is an interesting &amp; innovative public space project under the Gardiner Expressway in Toronto. Monocle’s podcast <a href="https://monocle.com/radio/shows/the-urbanist/tall-stories-121/">The Urbanist</a> has an episode about this place - check it out!</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Read</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.blogto.com/">blogTO</a> is a great daily source for local news and culture, restaurant reviews, event. They have great neighbourhood guide, too.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/0415551803/?coliid=I21C5ELC8GWTGM&amp;colid=A09D2EGNMYW7&amp;psc=0&amp;ref_=lv_ov_lig_dp_it">The Exposed City: Mapping the Urban Invisibles</a> is a book for all the map lovers. The author is from the University of Toronto, and it focuses on urban elements that are invisible to the human eye.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The very unique Canadian magazine <a href="http://spacing.ca/about/">Spacing</a> that covers urban affairs in the country, of course, has a brunch in Toronto. <a href="http://spacing.ca/toronto/">Spacing Toronto</a> is a great introducing and a daily information resource for urbanists.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you love arts - <a href="https://canadianart.ca/">Canadian Art</a> is the preeminent platform for journalism and criticism about art and culture in Canada.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://oldto.sidewalklabs.com/">OldTO</a> (Old Toronto) is an open-source map tool created by above mentioned <a href="(https://sidewalktoronto.ca/)">Sidewalk Labs</a>. It provides block-by-block browsing of historic Toronto photographs. It's a great way to gather scattered memories to a communal platform.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2>Organization</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.globalcitiesinstitute.org">Global Cities Institute</a> is initiated by the University of Toronto in <a href="https://www.daniels.utoronto.ca/">the Daniels Faculty of Architecture, Landscape and Design</a>. It deals with various urban data to calculate, analyze and visualize in order to seek for alternative and progressive forms of urbanization.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A non-profit applied research organization <a href="http://www.canurb.org/">The Canadian Urban Institute</a> has a variety of programs and educational events to join, with is developed around the theme of healthy urban development.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you have graduated from a Masters, LLB, JD or Ph.D. program within the last three years,<a href="https://www.toronto.ca/home/jobs/information-for-applicants/recruitment-initiatives/toronto-urban-fellows/">Toronto Urban Fellows</a> by the city of Toronto could be your next very interesting career path.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.myseumoftoronto.com/">Myseum of Toronto</a> is not like a regular museum - it’s every place in the city. You can participate Myseum programs all year long at exhibits, online, and at pop-up events around the city. I like it when they say &quot;You are the “my” in Myseum&quot;, meaning that we can share our own stories, ideas, arts and music with them!</p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/toronto/Introduction/med/toronto01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Things we can learn from zoning]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vancouver/zoning</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vancouver/zoning</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/zoning/med/zoning.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Thor Alvis on Unsplash</em></p>
<p>The other day I've participated in a walking tour which had a quite unique catchphrase - &quot;Vancouver's Worst Zoning?&quot;. The event was organized by <a href="http://www.abundanthousingvancouver.com">Abundant Housing Vancouver</a>, which is a pro-housing group that supports additional housing of all types in Metro Vancouver.</p>
<p>I live in an area called Kitsilano, which is a relatively low-density residential neighborhood with a fantastic location bonus of being close to the beaches and parks, UBC, and even downtown. According to <a href="https://vancouver.ca/files/cov/Zoning-Map-Vancouver.pdf">this zoning map</a>, this area I currently live in is largely zoned as the Two-Family Dwelling Districts. However, recently the landlady and my roommates have passionately started talking about the city's re-zoning plan which might hugely effect this peaceful neighborhood. Why does zoning matter that much?</p>
<hr>
<p>The thing is, zoning explains a lot about how our cities work and how urban planning affects our everyday living. that's why the event was quite successful, in a way that lets people pay attention to statistics, demography and the density, city regulations, and understand why certain forms of urban environment are created in specific ways.</p>
<p><img alt="Vancouver's worst zoning01" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/zoning/med/zoning0.jpg"><br>
<em>One of the abandoned lots</em><br>
<img alt="Vancouver's worst zoning02" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/zoning/med/zoning1.jpg"></p>
<p>We gathered at West Point Grey neighborhood, where the members of Abundant Housing Vancouver claim as one of the places of &quot;Vancouver's worst zoning&quot;. This area is zoned RS-1, One-Family Dwelling, which itself is not uncommon. However, according to them, the city requires a minimum lot area to be 12,000 to 18,000 square feet, which is more than 4 times larger than the medium lot size for a house in Vancouver.</p>
<h2>Housing crisis is real in Vancouver.</h2>
<p>A new <a href="https://globalnews.ca/news/4366644/foreign-buyers-population-growth-carry-the-most-blame-for-metro-vancouver-housing-crisis-survey/">survey</a> finds that 90% of residents agree there’s a housing crisis in Metro Vancouver. Housing affordability is at a critical level, which makes Vancouver the most expensive housing market in the country.</p>
<p>On the other hand, I was quite surprised when I learned that multiple dwelling apartments are illegal on 76% of Vancouver's residential land. It means that the MAJOR parts of the city have the potential to supply relatively affordable, multi-family housings for more people, but the city is simply failing it.</p>
<p><img alt="Vancouver's worst zoning03" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/zoning/med/zoning2.jpg"><br>
<em>Construction of another single-house family housing</em><br>
<img alt="Vancouver's worst zoning04" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/zoning/med/zoning3.jpg"></p>
<p>On the tour, they explained that they believe building more housing is part of the solution to the housing crisis in Vancouver, and zoning for expensive, low-density housing (<em>cough</em> - such as the West Point Grey neighborhood) is part of the problem. If we can build more multiple dwelling apartments on 76% of Vancouver's residential land, we have more affordable space for everyone.</p>
<h2>Check the statistics and maps!</h2>
<p>Let's look at more statistics. According to 2016 Census, there are only 402 people living in West Point Grey neighborhood - Land per person is app. <strong>16,362</strong> square feet in West Point Grey neighborhood, and app. <strong>465</strong> square feet in West End. Wow.</p>
<p>Moreover, they told us about this interactive <a href="https://mountainmath.ca/map/assessment">map</a> by <a href="https://mountainmath.ca/">MountainMath Maps</a>(this website is AWESOME by the way, if you're interested in data and spatial analytics of Vancouver in general) is quite informative with a variety of visualization of Metro Vancouver's housing data. Just check the relative land value of each residential blocks in the city, and then change the map type to <a href="https://mountainmath.ca/map/assessment?zoom=13&amp;lat=49.2657&amp;lng=-123.149&amp;layer=10&amp;mapBase=2">tax density</a> - and wow, you should notice that there are some discrepancies. West Point Grey neighborhood, especially, has <strong>very low tax revenues per square meter of land</strong>, which is also part of a problem. The city is not even making the best out of it.</p>
<p>(<a href="https://mountainmath.ca/assessment_gl/map?zoom=12.458333333333334&amp;lat=49.2759&amp;lng=-123.1726">This map</a> shows tax density by heights, not by colors, so it might be easier to compare)</p>
<h2>How can we deal with re-zoning better?</h2>
<p>Rezoning changes how urban properties can be used or developed. Property owners and the City of Vancouver can <a href="https://rezoning.vancouver.ca/applications/">apply</a> for rezoning, and they have the power to support development objectives. Of course, upzoning and building more and more apartments do not simply solve the deep‐rooted housing crisis of the city, and there are many concerns by current residents that upzoning might destroy a character and charm of a neighborhood.</p>
<p>That's why we can't jump to a simple, short-term solution. However, as the walking tour by Abundant Housing Vancouver taught us, there are many lessons to be learned by understanding zoning, and how problematic it can be when a city is not doing anything to make it better.</p>
<hr>
<p>Additional resources to check out:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vancouver.ca/your-government/vanmap.aspx">VanMap</a> is an online map provided by the city in which you can check property lines and assessed values, zoning districts, amenities, and services etc.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you are curious about how the West Point Grey neighborhood would look like, <a href="https://vimeo.com/corbiefieldwalkerstudio">Corbie Fieldwalker Studio</a> made some short films about abandoned multi-million housings in the area - such as <a href="https://vimeo.com/151798667">Belmont Avenue | $25.8 Million</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/zoning/med/zoning.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Urbanism-Related Things to do and read @Yogyakarta]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/yogyakarta/Introduction</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/yogyakarta/Introduction</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/yogyakarta/Introduction/med/yogyakarta01.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Ali Yahya on Unsplash</em></p>
<p><em>It is a series profiling interesting urban projects, reading lists, initiatives, and places for urbanists to get the gist of what is happening in a city at a glance. <a href="mailto:travelingcircusofurbanism@gmail.com">Email me</a> if you, or someone you know, wants to introduce about your city!</em></p>
<p><em>The content of this post was curated and written by a talented architect <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/puspitaningtyas?originalSubdomain=id">Puspitaningtyas Sulistyowati</a> with deep local knowledge and passion. Follow her website <a href="https://sketchmemories.wordpress.com/">here</a> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/f_tyas/">instagram</a></em></p>
<hr>
<h3>Places to go, projects to check out</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Kota Gede is an old town settlement area and the former-Mataram Kingdom. Here, you can find an old mosque built in Mataram era, called <a href="https://www.indonesia-tourism.com/forum/showthread.php?1480-The-Great-Mosque-of-Kotagede-Yogyakarta-Indonesia">Great Mosque Kotagede Mataram</a>. There is a mix of many types of building here, from Kalang House to Colonial style. Check out some workshop by a talented silversmith from <a href="https://www.airasiafoundation.com/social-enterprise/selaka-kotagede/">Selaka Kota Gede</a> and take your chance to buy or (if you lucky) make a beautiful silver-craft by yourself.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://tourjogja.com/read/18/jalan-malioboro-the-24-hours-street.html">Malioboro street</a> is famous for street markets. Along this street, there are also many old buildings and attractions - I highly recommend a visit.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>You can find many interesting cafés and bars along the Prawirotaman street. This is a popular place not only for locals, but for foreigners, too.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com.sg/Attraction_Review-g294230-d379334-Reviews-Water_Castle_Tamansari-Yogyakarta_Java.html">Taman sari</a> is a complex of old royal bathing place surrounded by old kampung, where the royal servant families used to live.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://artjog.co.id/">Artjog</a> is a big art event that happens everywhere in Yogyakarta to feature talented artists. This event held yearly, and the next event will be 25 July - 25 August 2019. Don't miss it!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://yats.co/">YATS.Colony</a> is a new unique hotel designed by a local architect. Try to spend at least a night here.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.arte-util.org/projects/bumi-pemuda-rahayu/">Bumi Pemuda Rahayu</a> is a cultural and community center, located in Gunung Kidul area, close to Pinus forest and Bukit Bintang. Every program or event supports community development of this area, and there is also a community bamboo crafter group. Check more information on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/bumipemudarahayu/">Bumi Pemuda Rahayu Projects</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Meet this inspirational barista whose name is <a href="http://www.cikopi.com/2013/09/pepeng-dan-klinik-kopi/">Mas Pepeng</a>, the owner of <a href="http://www.klinikkopi.com/">Klinik kopi</a>. He supports local coffee farmers to develop better quality products and sell their products in his shop. This coffee shop has a unique style of service - manual brew and direct service with a barista. No wifi connection here, so you can spend the time chatting and meeting with people. Follow their Instagram <a href="https://www.instagram.com/klinikkopi/">here</a>.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Read</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Find interesting contemporary art events and places around Yogyakarta <a href="http://artmapjogja.com/">here</a> - Yogyakarta Contemporary Art Map is easy to read and fun to use!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Read <a href="https://www.inditales.com/kota-gede-old-town-yogyakarta/">this article</a> and learn more about lively Kota Gede.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2>Organization</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://arkomjogja.or.id/">Arkom jogja</a> is a community architect network in Yogyakarta. They build not only physical things but also focus on building the community. Follow their <a href="https://www.instagram.com/arkomjogja/">instagram</a> and learn more about their projects such as reconstruction acts after a disaster, community urban planning, community heritage conservation, and developing local techniques and materials.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://arkomjogja.or.id/kalijawi/">Paguyuban Kalijawi</a> is a grassroots organization that lives along the riverside of Winongo river and Gajah Wong river. They have built some bamboo-made community centers and infrastructure for their members’ kampung. Follow their Instagram <a href="https://www.instagram.com/paguyuban_kalijawi/">here</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://kunci.or.id/">KUNCI</a> is an organization center with a focus on art and cultural studies.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.viaviajogja.com/">Via Via</a> focuses on cultural and tourism issue in Yogyakarta.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/yyaf_id/">YYAF</a> is Yogyakarta's Young Architect Forum.</p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/yogyakarta/Introduction/med/yogyakarta01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Confronting the history of discrimination and exclusion: Komagata Maru Memorial]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vancouver/komagatamaruincident</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vancouver/komagatamaruincident</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>The other day, I finally visited a monument that I've been wanting to visit for many years. <a href="http://www.vancouversun.com/life/komagata+maru+passengers+remembered+with+vancouver+monument/6978053/story.html">Komagata Maru Memorial</a> is located along the seawall near Convention Centre West in Vancouver - silent, but very powerful place to learn about the hidden history of Canada's discriminatory act. I decided to write about this place here, because collective/historical memories are/should be related to space and place.</p>
<h2>Komagata Maru incident</h2>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/komagatamaruincident/med/komagatamaru1.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/komagatamaruincident/med/komagatamaru2.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/komagatamaruincident/med/komagatamaru3.jpg"><br>
<em>The monument made by steel panels blends well into its green surrounding landscape. It simulates the ships hull, and it includes the curved names of all the passengers denied entry</em></p>
<p>The Komagata Maru incident was one of the most notorious incidents in the history of early 20th century Canada, which is part of exclusionary laws that were designed to keep out immigrants of Asian origin from the country.</p>
<p>Komagata Maru was a 55 steam liner - it arrived at Vancouver port with 376 passengers from Punjab, India, seeking to immigrate to Canada.</p>
<p>Most of the passengers were not allowed to land in Canada and the ship was forced to return. It has been argued and recognized as the epitome of Canada's racist past. In the memorial, you can get a historical narrative of the incident, and imagine their despair with the cascading waves of Vancouver’s harbor.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/komagatamaruincident/med/komagatamaru4.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/komagatamaruincident/med/komagatamaru5.jpg"></p>
<h2>History comes along</h2>
<p>More than a full century after the incident, Komagata Maru's story is still relevant though. A friend of mine who was with me at the memorial told me about [MV Sun Sea incident](MV Sun Sea incident) - MV Sun Sea is a cargo ship that brought 492 Sri Lankan Tamils into British Columbia in 2010. They escaped from Sri Lankan Civil War, but the Conservative government at the time took an aggressive stance, in order to prevent future “irregular arrivals&quot;.</p>
<p>Today, the vessel is still afloat alongside moored on the Fraser River across from Fisheries &amp; Oceans Canada in BC. History does come along in a very harsh way, that's why it matters that we remember.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/komagatamaruincident/med/komagatamaru0.jpg"></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/komagatamaruincident/med/komagatamaru4.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Walk Strathcona, and check out Vancouver's registered heritage buildings]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vancouver/strathcona</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vancouver/strathcona</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>Strathcona is not a tourist destination by any means, but it is one of Vancouver's earliest neighborhoods and has a lot to offer to gratify urbanist's curiosity.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona0.jpg"><br>
<em>Lord Strathcona School, built in 1897</em></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona1.jpg"><br>
<em>The Principal's House</em></p>
<p>Every summer, Regulatory Authority <a href="https://aibc.ca/">The Architectural Institute of British Columbia (AIBC) </a> offers Architectural Walking Tours featuring six Vancouver and three Victoria neighborhoods, to engage and educate participants about the value of architecture and built environment and its integral role within society.</p>
<p>With a knowledgeable guide from AIBC, I joined a tour that featured Strathcona neighborhood to learn about its historical<br>
value.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona2.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona10.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona7.jpg"></p>
<p>Strathcona is a neighborhood of residential houses and apartment buildings, bordered by Chinatown to the west, and Canadian National Railway and Great Northern Railway classification yards to the south.</p>
<p>Since the city's founding in 1886 until 1920, the population of Strathcona grew significantly, as its convenient location as a railway terminus. Strathcona has always been a working-class neighborhood, and it has been known by its diverse residents from many ethnic backgrounds. For instance, <a href="http://www.vancouverheritagefoundation.org/place-that-matters/hogans-alley/">Hogan’s Alley</a>, the nucleus of Vancouver’s first concentrated black community, was located at the southwestern edge of Strathcona (Watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ANX5kYh-8dc">this video</a> to learn more).</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona4.jpg"><br>
<em>In Strathcona, the majority of residents speak Chinese</em><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona14.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona17.jpg"></p>
<h1>Fight against a massive redevelopment scheme of public housing</h1>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona6.jpg"><br>
In the 1950s, City planners earmarked Strathcona for demolition as part of a massive urban renewal program to build public housing - the redevelopment would have wiped out most of the historical unique buildings in the neighborhood, introducing new block upon block of identical apartments buildings and townhouses. It also included a plan for creating an inner city freeway, which would have destructed some parts of Gastown and Chinatown. (I am glad that the plan was ultimately stopped - However, construction of the first phase demolished part of Hogan’s Alley - a heart of black community (check <a href="http://blackstrathcona.com/">Black Strathcona</a>).</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona3.jpg"><br>
<em>One of the residential house that was featured during the tour</em><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona5.jpg"></p>
<p>Strathcona residents mobilized in opposition. They argued for the retention and renovation of the area's eclectic mix of housing but by the time the redevelopment proposals were shelved 15 blocks of the neighborhood had already been demolished. In 1968, the community convinced federal, provincial and municipal governments to support a $5 million rehabilitation project that included homes, street and sidewalk repairs, and the creation of new parks.</p>
<p>They managed to demolish some blocks of the neighborhood - however, the massive renewal plan itself was called off thanks to opposition from the community, led by residents.</p>
<h1>Restoration and heritage registration created a beautiful eclectic mix of housings</h1>
<p>In 1968, they succeeded to convince the government to a $5 million rehabilitation project, in order to restore homes, street, sidewalk, and parks.</p>
<p>Now, Strathcona has one of the largest concentrations of 19th and early 20th century buildings in Vancouver, with a unique mix of architectural styles. Some of them are almost 100 years old and are registered as heritage buildings.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona8.jpg"></p>
<p>You can take a walk in the neighborhood, observing some unique old houses. There is usually a sign if a building is registered as a heritage, which in some cases has been supported by grants from the &quot;<a href="http://www.vancouverheritagefoundation.org/restoreit.html">Restore It!</a>&quot; program from Vancouver Heritage Foundation.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona12.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona11.jpg"><br>
<em>One of the restored buildings - it has decorative garages in respect of its original shape and feature</em></p>
<p>Styles range from famous <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vancouver_Special">Vancouver special</a> to large &quot;Queen Anne&quot; homes decorated with elaborate brackets and shingle work.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona13.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona9.jpg"></p>
<p>It's been said that Strathcona has been subjected to a significant gentrification process in recent years, due to housing stock restoration is raising property values. This process might completely change the demography of residents in the neighborhood, attracting wealthier house owners. Strathcona is still in the process of change - that is why it is very interesting to go a little bit further than downtown, to check out one of the unique neighborhoods in Vancouver now.</p>
<p>Reference:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://vancouver.ca/news-calendar/strathcona.aspx">City of Vancouver</a></li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/strathcona/med/Strathcona0.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ City Conversations about Vancouver Waterfront]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vancouver/waterfront</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vancouver/waterfront</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/waterfront/med/waterfront04.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Aditya Chinchure on Unsplash</em></p>
<p>I visited <a href="https://waterfrontseattle.org/">Friends of Waterfront</a> in Seattle last month to learn about <a href="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment">the future of Seattle's waterfront</a>. They are already in a phase of implementing their concrete action plan, explaining it to citizens and having them involved.</p>
<p>It seems like Seattle is not the only one in the game of reimagining its urban waterfront though. While it is still a phase of calling for a comprehensive plan, Vancouver also has been talking about the future of their waterfront.</p>
<p>The other day, there was <a href="https://www.sfu.ca/publicsquare/upcoming-events/city-conversations.html">SFU City Conversations</a> by <a href="http://www.sfu.ca/publicsquare.html">SFU Public Square</a> to have a conversation about the Waterfront with citizens.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/waterfront/med/waterfront0.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/waterfront/med/waterfront1.jpg"></p>
<p><a href="https://georgiastrait.org/">The Georgia Strait Alliance</a> recently published <a href="http://www.waterfrontinitiative.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Waterfront-Full-Report-Web.pdf">a report</a> that summarizes the current state/potential of the Waterfront.<br>
The report is a great piece of work, and, in my opinion, worth reading.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/waterfront/med/waterfront3.jpg"></p>
<p>The Waterfront Initiative has been an exercise since 2013 - they have been spending 5 years in facilitating broad stakeholder conversation and networking. Their goal is to manage the interface between land and sea and have a great waterfront like in the New York City and other cities. The report focuses on five key themes — working, living, access to nature, ecosystems, and transportation.</p>
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sl6SOY2gI5U" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>
*Waterfront Cities of the World: Vancouver*
<p>At the open-air conversation that took place in a public park just steps away from the Burrard inlet, the expats spoke only about 20 mins - the rest of the time was dedicated to participants; citizens. The conversation went from swim-ability of the water, the leadership of the redevelopment initiative, and ironically, lack of conversation between expats and citizens to create a big vision together.</p>
<p>If you are interested in Waterfront development in other cities, I would recommend keeping an eye on the process of how the discussion would develop in Vancouver from now on. All the waterfront is different, obviously, but we can learn from a process itself about how we build a comprehensive plan from scratch with help of citizens.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Read the <a href="http://www.waterfrontinitiative.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/SnapshotReportWeb.pdf">report summary</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Read the <a href="http://www.waterfrontinitiative.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/Waterfront-Full-Report-Web.pdf">full report</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/waterfront/med/waterfront04.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Vancouver's successful model for brownfield redevelopment: Granville Island]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vancouver/granvilleisland</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vancouver/granvilleisland</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland0.jpg"><br>
<a href="https://granvilleisland.com/">Granville Island</a> is one of the most popular touristic destinations and a bustling public space in Vancouver, but it is also a site that had <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/1970s-granville-island-redevelopment-1.4021855">significant impact on Vancouver's urban design history</a>. If you ever get a chance to visit Granville Island, I would recommend paying attention to not only the unique markets and art galleries, but also the urban design/planning decision and history behind it.</p>
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-YFavdWspTQ" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<h2>Industrial heritage and a place for people</h2>
<p>Up until the late 1970s, Granville Island was a mere industrial wasteland, nestled under the Granville Street Bridge on False Creek.</p>
<p>Granville Island was completed in 1916, using material dredged from False Creek. It was to create 41 acres of land to be used by industry, and over 40 years various factories thrived on the island while the city of Vancouver grew around it.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland11.jpg"><br>
<em>Old pictures from the past, spotted on a building window</em></p>
<p>What happened then? A same old story -in the 1960s, many of the industries began to move out due to changing market. The remaining were left dirty, and the land was heavily contaminated. You can check some pictures from the old days <a href="https://granvilleisland.com/history-and-architecture">here</a>.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland1.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland2.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland3.jpg"></p>
<p>In 1973, The Canadian government assigned the Island to the Canada Mortgage and Housing Corporation (CMHC) for the management and redevelopment of the land, and this is when all the urban development started that shapes the island as it is now.</p>
<p>It was agreed between The Canadian government and CMHC that the Granville Island would become a &quot;people place&quot;, accessible to everyone. At the same time, it should stay reflective of its industrial maritime heritage, by re-using existing buildings as much as possible.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland6.jpg"><br>
<em>The Public Market opened in 1979</em><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland7.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland4.jpg"></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland5.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland8.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland9.jpg"></p>
<h2>Unique, organic development</h2>
<p>Granville Island is federal land, that is why there was unique (rather loose) zoning and other criteria were applied during the development - they broke so many of the accepted rules of public space. This is how the current beautifully-messy(!) urban space was shaped.</p>
<p>I would end with this quote - which accurately depicts how it is like to be in Granville Island today.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Under federal control, the result was a mishmash of vehicle and pedestrian traffic that creates an urban space unlike anything else in the city — to say nothing of the mixed-use zoning that saw an active public market almost next door to a still-operating nail factory. - <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/1970s-granville-island-redevelopment-1.4021855">Matt Meuse</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland13.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland14.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland15.jpg"></p>
<p>I highly recommend a visit!</p>
<p>Reference:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.pps.org/article/how-granville-island-came-to-be">HOW GRANVILLE ISLAND CAME TO BE</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/1970s-granville-island-redevelopment-1.4021855">How Granville Island changed the course of Vancouver urban design history</a></li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/granvilleisland/med/granvilleisland0.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ City and migration: Interview with Sankar Raman from The Immigrant Story]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/portland/immigrantstory</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/portland/immigrantstory</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>During my stay in Portland, I encountered a very inspiring project called <a href="(https://theimmigrantstory.org/)">The Immigrant Story</a>, which collects stories and photographs of immigrants in order to document/archive their voices.</p>
<p>Sankar Raman, a founder of the project and a Northwest digital art photographer, believes that <strong>“The Immigrant Story is the American story.”</strong></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/immigrantstory/med/Sankar-Raman-by-kim.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Kim Nguyen</em></p>
<p>I’ve been always curious about the everyday life of immigrants in cities and how they experience cities. I interviewed Mr. Raman to learn more about the project and to hear what he thinks about the topic of city and migration.</p>
<hr>
<h3>Background - rising wave of racism</h3>
<p><em><strong>Thank you so much for the time today. First, could you tell me a little bit about the background of the project?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Mr. Sankar:</strong> The first idea of the project was born right after the elections in 2017. During this time, the immigrants are increasingly becoming a scapegoat — and there is a growing tension and a divisive political rhetoric that makes us divided with “us versus them” mindset. I was not politically active and am not a political person, but I felt an urge to do something about it.</p>
<p>Let me tell you a real example that happened here in Portland. There was a little girl called Fatemah, she was from Iran and she was supposed to come to Oregon Health &amp; Science University to go through her heart surgery. She and her family came from Iran to Dubai and were on their way to here in Portland, and it was exactly the time the Muslim ban went into effect. Because of the ban, she could not travel to Portland.</p>
<p>It became a big issue here; everybody was protesting. And it was then I realized that it is not just political rhetoric but real people (who) are getting affected by changes in policies made against immigrants. That has come to affect people in our community here in Portland.</p>
<h3>Creating the counter-narratives</h3>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/immigrantstory/med/immigrantstory.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Nitish Meena on Unsplash</em></p>
<p><strong>Mr. Sankar:</strong> I was not a storyteller or a writer, but I decided to start producing a <strong>counter-narrative</strong> against the dominant political rhetoric, which was portraying the immigrants as murderers, rapists and from shithole countries.</p>
<p>When you really look at the history of this country, everybody here came from somewhere else. Some of us came recently, some of us came years ago, some of us came (on the) Mayflower, some of us came 10,000 years ago. The fact remains that the country is built on the people who come here from the outside, and so it is rightfully called a nation of immigrants.</p>
<p><em><strong>I agree</strong></em></p>
<p>So how do we create change? I thought the way to do this is making the human connection by telling the real stories of immigrants. These stories are short form human interest narratives, and published with close-up portraits. We also make very large prints and showcase these stories as a gallery exhibition to create conversations.</p>
<p>When I first started writing stories and sharing these stories, my wife was the editor, so for the first few months we did all the publishing work by ourselves. After a few trials, I was really fortunate that so many high-quality journalists started to help us out.</p>
<p>Today, there are more than 20 volunteers sharing their talents and skills to create a very high quality content for our project. These folks are talented journalists, writers, photographers. Some of them worked for local newspapers or other big media outlets like the Los Angeles Times or Washington Post. We also have graphic designers, web developers and visual artists volunteering with us. More information about their site can be found <a href="https://theimmigrantstory.org/our-story/">here</a>.</p>
<h3>The art of listening</h3>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/immigrantstory/med/immigrantstory02.jpg"><br>
<em>Reference: Sankar Raman/The Immigrant Story</em></p>
<p><em><strong>I’ve been curious why you picked storytelling as your methodology to tackle the challenge. So it is about the human connection, creating empathy among people, isn’t it?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Mr. Sankar:</strong> Yes, exactly. I mean, when I hear about your personal story, for instance, there’s no way I can hate you, right?</p>
<p>We spend about two hours with each interviewee and learn about their life — where the person was born, what the person does, how was the life before coming to (the) U.S. etc. We also spend a lot of time and energy in crafting the story so that it comes out really authentic.</p>
<p><em><strong>How do you find these people to interview with?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Mr. Sankar:</strong> I really enjoy meeting people, and whenever I meet people, I am always curious about the stories behind them. When they have an interesting story to tell I write it down and ask them if they want to be part of this project to share their stories. That is my main way of finding people to interview,.</p>
<p>I am very curious to gather all these stories of diaspora, refugees and human displacements due to conflicts. These are very important stories to be documented.</p>
<h3>Urban narratives and immigrant’s relationship with cities</h3>
<p><em><strong>I am curious about the relationship between the city of Portland and The Immigrant Story. How does the city affect your idea?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Mr.Sankar:</strong> Portland is a very progressive city. However, it still acts like a white city, and we still have problems.</p>
<p>In this part of town (Northwest), most of them are tech workers like me, working in Nike and Intel etc., and people are very diverse. This diversity, for some reason for me, I could navigate through that. I have not experienced any issues racially from my experience living in this part of the town.</p>
<p>However, when I started this project, I started going to the other parts of the city such as Southeast Portland. Different parts of the city have (their) own different cultural mix. There I see different elements of racial undercurrent at play at different levels.</p>
<p>For example, about a year ago, there was a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2017_Portland_train_attack">stabbing incident in the MAX</a> Train and two people were stabbed to death here in Portland. This kind of thing happens in Portland. Not often, but it happens.</p>
<p><em><strong>I’m always curious about how immigrants experience the city, how they move here and interact with other communities, and how they experience discrimination and challenges. That’s why it’s really important to listen to personal stories, because they can only be truly understood by personal experiences.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Mr.Sankar:</strong> Exactly. Right now, we have an exhibition, that is been shown at <a href="(http://www.ojmche.org/)">the Oregon Jewish Museum</a> in downtown. We call it “<a href="https://theimmigrantstory.org/who-we-are/">Who We Are</a>.” It is a collection of stories of six muslim women from Portland that we designed to explore their emotions.</p>
<p>In these stories we profile the immigrant experience, a sort of oral history of our community. It is kind of a indicator of how the community was feeling at that time. In some of the these stories, you could see the raw emotions, the intensity of their feelings in these stories. It is through their personal experiences, through that lens so to speak, we explore race, identity and culture.</p>
<h3>Place to celebrate diversity</h3>
<p><em><strong>What is your next step?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Mr. Sankar:</strong> I have a big vision.</p>
<p>There are museums and memorials for many things, but we don’t have one to signify the achievements and accomplishments of immigrants in this country. I want to change that.</p>
<p>My goal is to create a museum that explores the immigration and their accomplishments. Just imagine a museum that has a floor that talks about Irish immigrants, another floor about Eastern European immigrants, etc.<br>
These are all different people who came from different continents, and we should display their accomplishments.</p>
<p>I want to have a place where we celebrate it. I think it’s important to have an actual place where you can bring people in and explore visually. When you do that, you won't be able to speak ill of immigrants then.</p>
<h3>We all travel</h3>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/immigrantstory/med/imigratntstory03.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Barth Bailey on Unsplash. We all travel</em></p>
<p><em><strong>I like the way you interchangeably use the term “immigrants” to represent everyone. To you it implies everyone; it’s not only the people who arrived recently!</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Mr. Sankar:</strong> Yeah, everybody! Basically, we are all immigrants. We all migrate continuously for some reason or the other.</p>
<p>Let me tell you one story of myself, which is very personal to me. I came from a very small village in India — a very small community, and nobody knows how long our community has been there in that village.</p>
<p>But then, when I do my DNA, it says I traveled through the spice route — meaning that I came from somewhere from the Middle East, and they have traveled over the years through that spice route to the Indian subcontinent through Iran, Afghanistan, through Pakistan to India, and then came down to south of India.</p>
<p>My point is that the path my ancestors took is a true way to understand human beings. Humans travel — and not only humans but their cultures, languages, food, etc., with them. We have to keep it that way!</p>
<p><em><strong>I agree. I can’t wait to see a place that celebrates diversity and migration. Thank you so much for the time today!</strong></em></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/immigrantstory/med/immigrantstory01.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Wellington Rodrigues on Unsplash</em></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/immigrantstory/med/immigrantstory01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Things to do and read for urbanists @Vancouver]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vancouver/Introduction</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vancouver/Introduction</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/Introduction/med/vancouver01.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Scott Webb on Unsplash</em></p>
<h3>Things to do, places/project to check out</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/app/id1050472181">UBC Vantage Walking Tour</a> is an educational app to learn the history of Downtown Vancouver.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Affordable housing projects in Gastown.<br>
Read: <a href="https://www.huffingtonpost.ca/2014/07/11/co-op-housing-vancouver_n_5531484.html">Co-op Housing In Vancouver Is The Affordable Option You Didn't Know About</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Read</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="http://thiscitylife.tumblr.com/">This City Life</a> is a city blog by urbanist, freelance writer and city lover <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jillian-glover-m-urb-apr-7981b98/">Jillian Glover</a>. The blog was nominated as one of <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/cities/interactive/2014/jan/27/best-city-blogs-interactive">the best city blogs</a> by the Guardian.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://spacing.ca/vancouver/">Spacing Vancouver</a> is a magazine, store, and blog network to think critically about how they can shape the public spaces that surround their everyday lives.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.vancouverisawesome.com/">Vancouver Is Awesome</a> is a online publication that shares everything about Vancouver, discussing about greatness and things to make people stay here. They have various <a href="https://www.vancouverisawesome.com/category/architecture/">architecture-related articles</a>, which are worth reading.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A friend of mine recommended me this <a href="https://brightoncollege.com/100-years-architecture-in-vancouver/">amazing infographic</a> that summaries 100 years of amazing architecture in Vancouver. This <a href="http://montecristomagazine.com/design/vancouvers-architectural-landmarks">Illustrations of Vancouver’s Architectural Landmarks</a> are great to check out as well!</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Organization, initiative</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.citystudiovancouver.com/">City Studio</a> launched in 2011 with collaboration of City of Vancouver and Simon Fraser University. It has some experimental projects toco-created solutions for the city together with City staff and community,</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Established in 1926, <a href="http://vancouverplanning.ca/">The Vancouver City Planning Commission</a> is an advisory body of volunteers appointed by Council and the City’s oldest citizens’ body.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://thehappycity.com/s">Happy City</a>uses lessons from psychology and public health to design happiness into neighborhoods and cities. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7WiQUzOnA5w">This TED talk</a> by Charles Montgomery is helpful to understand what happy city is really about.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.modacitylife.com/">Modacity</a> by Chris and Melissa Bruntlett, co-authors of the book “Building the Cycling City: The Dutch Blueprint for Urban Vitality”. This might be interesting for bike lovers!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://urbanarium.org/">Urbanarium</a> is a group of the most committed urbanites in Vancouver, including architects, planners and other citizens who are passionate about city making. They have various events such as city debateS and bike tours!</p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vancouver/Introduction/med/vancouver01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ 2 truly inspiring Affordable Housing Projects in Seattle]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/seattle/affordablehousing</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/seattle/affordablehousing</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>The other day I participated an event by <a href="https://www.theurbanist.org/">the Urbanist</a> about <a href="https://www.theurbanist.org/2018/08/07/building-community-in-southeast-seattle-tour-this-saturday/">Housing Community in South Seattle</a>(they organize a lot of great events and meetups for all city lovers - <a href="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment">this post</a> is also based on their walking tour).</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/affordablehousing/med/affordablehousing03.jpg"></p>
<p>Like all the other major cities in the world, Seattle is rapidly changing and growing, and unfortunately, becoming increasingly unaffordable. That is why it is crucial to discuss the importance of affordable housing for lower-income residents at risk of displacement.</p>
<p>We took the Link light rail and visited South Seattle to learn more about affordable housing projects that have been invested by the city government for many years.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/affordablehousing/med/affordablehousing00.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Tom Rumble on Unsplash</em></p>
<p>First all - what is 'affordable housing' anyway? Many people assume that it means low-cost housings. There are many definitions of affordable housing, but the answer is No - at least it's more complicated than that. There are many poorly constructed low-valued housings out there, but if there is no rent regulation, an owner can charge serious price from tenants, and it is not 'affordable' anymore. Instead, affordable housing should involve some public subsidy or other kind of non-profit investment, as well as rent control to cater to a certain section of society whose income is below the median household income.</p>
<ul>
<li>Plaza Roberto Maestas</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/affordablehousing/med/affordablehousing01.jpg"></p>
<p>First, we visited <a href="http://beacondevgroup.com/locations/plaza-roberto-maestas/">Plaza Roberto Maestas</a>, which is a landmark of equitable, community-inspired, transit-oriented development project in the heart of the Beacon Hill neighborhood of Seattle. There are the Beacon Hill Light Rail Station and the El Centro de la Raza schoolhouse right next to the housing block.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/affordablehousing/med/affordablehousing02.jpg"></p>
<p>Completed in September 2016, this affordable housing consists of two six-story buildings that have an outdoor plaza, a multicultural community center, and office spaces. This is a great example of mixed-use development in a rapidly gentrifying neighborhood, historically occupied by Hispanic population.</p>
<p>There are some murals in the plaza, designed by local artists. All the signs and posters in the school have multiple languages that indicate that the multicultural nature of its community.</p>
<ul>
<li>Othello Square</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/affordablehousing/med/affordablehousing04.jpg"></p>
<p>The last visit was about <a href="https://homesightwa.org/community-development/real-estate-development/othellosquare">Othello Square</a>. The site is currently vacant and formerly known as the Southeast Economic Opportunity Center - once completed, Othello Square is going to be a welcoming mix-use shared space to invite people in Southeast Seattle (and beyond) to provide opportunities for higher education, jobs, and support to start and keep a business. There will be 265 apartments and for-sale homes, affordable retail and commercial space and community support services to help stabilize communities at risk of displacement.</p>
<p>Behind it, there is <a href="https://homesightwa.org/">HomeSight</a>, which has worked to preserve and promote economically and culturally-diverse communities through affordable homeownership, business development, and community advocacy.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/affordablehousing/med/chuttersnap-622242-unsplash.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by chuttersnap on Unsplash</em></p>
<p>Perhaps the crucial factor of success is not only focusing on the housing itself but people's actual lives around it - we need not only housings but also decent access to other social services. Along with affordable rental and ownership housing, other facilities are needed such as cultural/community centers, educational institutions such as schools, low-income medical clinics, childcare, offices/commercial space to support local economic growth.</p>
<p>In that way, we can learn a lot from these projects in Seattle who focus on their 'communities' and their real lives there.</p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/affordablehousing/med/affordablehousing03.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Freeway Park, an urban oasis that bridges over a highway]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/seattle/freewaypark</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/seattle/freewaypark</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark1.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark3.jpg"></p>
<p><a href="http://www.seattle.gov/parks/find/parks/freeway-park">Freeway Park</a> in downtown Seattle has a unique form as it bridges over Interstate 5 (one of the major highways in the U.S.) and a large city-owned parking lot. Designed by landscape architect Lawrence Halprin and Angela Danadjieva, this park opened in 1976, and it is widely considered to be one of the modernist masterpieces.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark23.jpg"></p>
<p>This is, in my opinion, one of the most beautiful 'urban' parks in the U.S. Instead of letting people escape from their tiring urban life to reconnect nature, it doesn't hide its beauty/ugliness of the city. It's over highway after all - meaning that you can hear roaring traffic and the squawk of car horns underneath the park, and you also can't help but catch a glimpse of the surrounding buildings. To me this is a very 'honest' approach - also, when we define park as a place where people can freely gather and mingle, this Freeway Park should be the one that does that.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark10.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark11.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark12.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark13.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark14.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark15.jpg"></p>
<p>Over five acres in size, you can never get bored in Freeway Park with a maze of unique architectural forms - such as concrete fountains, small plazas and winding small pathways as well as green lawns and various type of trees. Every block offers you a different feeling and experience that individually very unique, so it is fun to go there to find your own favorite spot.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark4.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark5.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark6.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark7.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark8.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark9.jpg"></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark16.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark17.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark18.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark19.jpg"></p>
<p>Community activities are active and there are always events happening. <a href="http://freewayparkassociation.org/">Freeway Park Association</a> is community driven non-profit organization, and it has been working alongside the Seattle Parks Department since 1993, to activate and advocate for Freeway Park. There are some boards on the site to check out the event schedule, as well as leaving your comment and idea on how to improve the park. What a lovely place!</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark20.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark21.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark2.jpg"></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/freewaypark/med/freewaypark1.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ The future of Waterfront Seattle]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront0.jpg"></p>
<p>I love <a href="https://www.theurbanist.org/">the Urbanist</a>, a Seattle-based non-profit organization who believes in cities as a unique platform for addressing many of the most difficult problems we face. They focus on writing and researching, as well as organizing educational events and Meetup to engage with citizens to discuss the future of cities.</p>
<p>I've been following their work and reading some of the most helpful articles by them, and this time I finally got a chance to join one of their event called Urbanist Walking Tour. This time the theme was about <a href="www.waterfrontseattle.org">The Waterfront Seattle</a>, where there is a massive urban renewal project going on.</p>
<h3>Background</h3>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/Illustrative-Site-Plan-Phase.jpg"><br>
<em>Completed map of the development plan from <a href="https://waterfrontseattle.org/overview">here</a></em></p>
<p>We visited <a href="https://waterfrontseattle.org/">Friends of Waterfront Seattle</a>, part of the City of Seattle's Office of the Waterfront, which is working closely with civic leaders, stakeholders, and the broader Seattle public to create a &quot;Waterfront for All.&quot; You can check out their <a href="https://waterfrontseattle.org/documents">Documents Library</a>, and this <a href="https://waterfrontseattle.org/Media/Default/Library/Presentations/2018_0807_Urbanist_WFS_FINAL_public.pdf">presentation</a> is particularly helpful to understand the project broadly.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront1.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront2.jpg"></p>
<p>The City of Seattle released a Concept Design, Framework / Strategic Plan in July 2012 to announce the overall vision for the waterfront. The Waterfront Seattle Program is transforming the area from Pioneer Square to Belltown, trying to (re)connect downtown Seattle and Elliott Bay.</p>
<p>Once Alaskan Way Viaduct is removed this year in 2018, the project will be working to create twenty acres of new and improved public space, multimodal surface streets along Alaskan Way and Elliott Way to serve all modes of travel, and better connections between center city neighborhoods and Elliott Bay.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront4.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront5.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront6.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront7.jpg"></p>
<p>When you walk along the waterfront, you see a lot of construction, as well as the beautifully dense urban scenery of downtown.<br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront8.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront9.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront10.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront11.jpg"></p>
<p>This <strong>Waterfront Park</strong> (pictures below) will also be rebuilt with an urban plaza and a children's playground.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront12.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront13.jpg"></p>
<p><strong>Harbor Steps</strong> is not exactly part of the Waterfront development, but I highly recommend to visit this great public space and sit down on the stairs. The view that overlooks the waterfront is now blocked by the highway, but it will be more vibrant after the improvement of Alaskan Way - which is going to have new traffic links to downtown, transit pathway and waterfront cycle track.<br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront14.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront15.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront16.jpg"></p>
<p>If you want to engage in this project or just curious about the future of waterfront holds - you can check out <a href="https://waterfrontseattle.org/community-engagement">Community Engagement</a> page by Friends of Waterfront Seattle to sign up for the email list, follow them on social media etc. I'm very much looking forward to coming back here after the project is done.</p>
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4La-8egv1bk" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>
*This video is also very helpful to understand the Alaskan Way Viaduct "The Alaskan Way Viaduct: How Seattle chose the Bertha tunnel alternative" - by [City Beautiful](https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCGc8ZVCsrR3dAuhvUbkbToQ)*
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/waterfrontdevelopment/med/waterfront0.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Things to do and read for urbanists @Seattle]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/seattle/Introduction</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/seattle/Introduction</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/Introduction/med/seattleinteroduction.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Michael Discenza on Unsplash</em></p>
<h3>Things to do, places/project to check out</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>If you are an urbanist you would love maps too. <a href="http://www.metskers.com/">Metsker Maps of Seattle</a> is considered to be the largest map store in the U.S.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Visit <a href="http://www.friendsofwaterfrontseattle.org/">Friends of Waterfront Seattle</a> to learn more about the waterfront urban development in Seattle.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Homelessness is one of the serious issues that all cities can relate to. Since 2008, <a href="https://www.pathwithart.org/">Path with Art</a> has been working to transform the lives of people recovering from homelessness, addiction, and other trauma by the power of art and creative engagement. I visited one of their exhibitions <a href="https://www.pathwithart.org/pearl-jam-collaboration">Unpacking Homelessness: A PATH WITH ART &amp; PEARL JAM COLLABORATION</a> during my stay there, and saw the posters that are designed by the artists who experiences homelessness. All the staffs there are so kind and warm - I highly recommend to visit there and have conversation with them.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Read</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://seattle.curbed.com/">Curbed Seattle</a> is always informative fun platform to check out.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Watch <a href="http://www.pbs.org/ten-that-changed-america/season-1/episode-3/">10 parks that changed America</a> and two of them are in Seattle!</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Organization, initiative</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.spacecityseattle.org/">Space.City</a> is an independent, not-for-profit organization dedicated to the discussion of art, architecture and urbanism. I participated one of their event during the stay in Seattle, in which they invited <a href="https://www.architectmagazine.com/design/maurice-coxs-detroit_o">Maurice Cox</a> from Detroit to discuss the urban dynamics that is happening in Detroit.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.theurbanist.org/">The Urbanist</a> is a non-profit organization that serves to examine and influence urban policies, and they have a bunch of quite interesting articles to read online. They also organize educational events / workshops to invite everyone to discuss the future of cities.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.aiaseattle.org/">AIA Seattle</a> is the architecture community based in Seattle.</p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/Introduction/med/seattleinteroduction.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Seattle's Gas Works Park: Since when did 'trash' become pretty?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/seattle/gasworkspark</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/seattle/gasworkspark</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/gasworkspark/med/gasworkspark3.jpg"></p>
<p>Gas Works Park in Seattle is one of the most influential public parks in the United States. Located on the shores of Lake Union, opposite side of downtown Seattle, this park opened to the public in 1975 on the location of a former coal gasification plant.</p>
<p>When you visit this 19-acre wide park, the first thing you notice is the giant remnants of the sole remaining coal gasification plant - which operated from 1906 to 1956. Now, nature took over the iconic ruin and it creates somehow mysterious and dynamic landscape that tells the history of the city.</p>
<h3>Landscape architect Richard Haag's controversial idea</h3>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/gasworkspark/med/gasworkspark12.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/gasworkspark/med/gasworkspark4.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/gasworkspark/med/gasworkspark8.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/gasworkspark/med/gasworkspark9.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/gasworkspark/med/gasworkspark10.jpg"></p>
<p>The park was designed by Seattle landscape architect Richard Haag, who proposed to the city to keep some of the remains of the gasification plant. According to his interview on the documentary <a href="https://www.pbs.org/video/geoffrey-baer-tours-10-changed-america-parks-9-gas-works-park-seattle/">10 Parks that Changed America</a> (by the way this documentary series is awesome. You can learn more about architecture and urbanism in the United States.), people found the idea crazy - and some still do. However, instead of ignoring/erasing the past, he pursued his idea of respecting the city's history and its iconic value.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/gasworkspark/med/gasworkspark0.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/gasworkspark/med/gasworkspark2.jpg"></p>
<p>The soil and groundwater of the site were contaminated during operation as a gasification plant, but after cleaning through bio-phytoremediation and other measures, this park is now the safe and joyful place to be in. Now you can get the breathtaking view over downtown Seattle from this park, as well as learning the history of its place through the ruins of the gas plant.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/gasworkspark/med/gasworkspark7.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/gasworkspark/med/gasworkspark5.jpg"></p>
<p>This park is a great reminder for the importance of public park in the heart of the city, where people can gather and connect without being worried about the safety or pollution. I highly recommend the visit to this park and praise the city's decision to convert one of the most neglected, contaminated land to the vibrant gathering space for citizens.</p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/seattle/gasworkspark/med/gasworkspark3.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[  Adaptive reuse project: a renovated historic elementary school Kennedy School by McMenamins]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/portland/KennedySchool</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/portland/KennedySchool</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<h3>McMenamins, a pioneer in the adaptive reuse field</h3>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool17.jpg"><br>
Started in 1974 by the McMenamins brothers, the Oregon-based company <a href="https://www.mcmenamins.com/">McMenamins</a> has been reusing old buildings that once served as schools, churches, theaters and homes.Their properties include historic hotels, pubs, concert venues and movie theaters, and all of them are whimsical and wonderfully special.</p>
<p>They recognized the local values and potentials of these abandoned buildings, as well as the environmental responsibility in restoring old buildings - they also use recycled materials wherever possible in new construction. Thus, McMenamins is a great example for adaptive reuse, adding new vales to the old buildings for the future while paying respect to their histories.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool12.jpg"></p>
<p>The other day, I visited one of their venues in Portland called <a href="https://www.mcmenamins.com/kennedy-school">Kennedy School</a> - which includes hotels, pubs, an event venue and a swimming pool, dining and movie theater.</p>
<h3>Kennedy School</h3>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool0.jpg"></p>
<p>Opened in 1915, The Kennedy School is a historic elementary school in northeast Portland. After it lost its function as a elementary school, it has been transformed into a 57-room hotel with a restaurant, multiple small bars, a movie theater, a swimming pool and a brewery.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool1.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool2.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool3.jpg"><br>
<em>It is also part of <a href="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/portland/Sundayparkways">BikeTown</a> area and has 4 racks</em></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool4.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool5.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool6.jpg"><br>
It is open for public and you can enter the building for free - it is very interesting to see the remaining structure of a elementary school and all the whimsical/fun art pieces on the walls.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool7.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool8.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool9.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool10.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool11.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool13.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool14.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool16.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool15.jpg"></p>
<p>I highly recommend for a visit, and watch a cheap movie / get drinks here, and enjoy how they breathe new life into this old building without failing to appreciate the beauty of the past.</p>
<p>References:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.meetingstoday.com/magazines/article-details/articleid/23520/title/mcmenamins-is-a-pioneer-in-the-adaptive-reuse-field">McMenamins is a pioneer in the adaptive reuse field</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.spiritedbiz.com/vision-versatility-story-mcmenamins/#slide-5">VISION AND VERSATILITY: THE STORY OF MCMENAMINS</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.ankrommoisan.com/blog/2016/04/05/mcmenamins-renovations-modernizing-future-while-honoring-past">McMenamins Renovations: Modernizing for the Future while Honoring the Past</a></li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/KennedySchool/med/kennedyschool17.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Things to do and read for urbanists @Portland]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/portland/Introduction</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/portland/Introduction</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Introduction/med/portland01.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Anna Holowetzki on Unsplash</em></p>
<h3>Things to do, places/project to check out</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>I love <a href="https://www.rebuildingcenter.org/">The ReBuilding Center</a> is Portland nonprofit organization, closely working with local communities through creative reuse of reclaimed materials - Similar concept with Austin's <a href="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/austin/CreativeReuse">Creative Reuse</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://albertamainst.org/shoplocal/visit/">Alberta Main Street</a> has a unique <a href="http://albertamainst.org/about/history/">history</a> and seems to have some very active community associations. It would be very interesting to join some of the <a href="http://albertamainst.org/calendar/">events</a> by Neighborhood Association.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Portland is a cycle capital in the United States and no one should leave the city without experiencing biking. <a href="https://www.biketownpdx.com/">BikeTown</a> is a great sharing bike service and <a href="http://www.pdxbikerentals.com/small-businessportland/">EVERYBODY'S BIKE RENTALS &amp; TOURS</a> is the one I got reccomended by a trustworthy local. Join the occasional <a href="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/portland/Sundayparkways">Sunday Parkways</a> to bike around the city without being interrupted by cars!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.mcmenamins.com/">Mcmenamins</a> is a great example in the field of adaptive reuse and the company has variety of beautiful buildings that you can visit, such as <a href="https://www.mcmenamins.com/kennedy-school">Kennedy School</a> and <a href="https://www.mcmenamins.com/bagdad-theater-pub">Bagdad Theater</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.pdxnm.com/">Portland Night Market</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.portlandoregon.gov/parks/69554">Movies in the park</a> is great for summer evening - the events are completely free and you can enjoy the quality of urban life.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Read</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>I enjoyed reading some articles recommended by one of my local friend, that explain rich history of North Williams Ave - once the vibrant heart of Portland’s Black community.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://blackwilliamsproject.com/">Black Williams Project</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.theskanner.com/news/history/11409-portland-gentrification-the-north-williams-avenue-that-was-1956-2011-08-09">Portland Gentrification: The North Williams Avenue that Was -- 1956</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>I can't stop loving this <a href="https://www.portlandoregon.gov/bps/article/480760">introduction document</a> about Portland's Central East district published by <a href="https://www.portlandoregon.gov/bps/">bureau of planning and sustainability Portland</a> - very informative and has great design.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>This academic thesis analyses Alberta district and explain how it transformed into arts district: <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B0DL9k4mI4KtT0VETUVtX1I5eHM/edit">RE-IMAGING A NEIGHBORHOOD:THE CREATION OF THE ALBERTA ARTS DISTRICT, PORTLAND, OREGON</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Organization, initiative</h3>
<ul>
<li>I can't stop admiring this initiative: <a href="https://theimmigrantstory.org/immigrant-story/">Immigrant Story</a>. They are based in Portland, collecting stories from immigrants who live in the city.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Introduction/med/portland01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Sunday for all the bike lovers - Sunday Parkways and Portland's exciting Green Loop Vision]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/portland/Sundayparkways</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/portland/Sundayparkways</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Sundayparkways/med/sundayparkways0.jpg"></p>
<p>I got lucky enough to be around in Portland when <a href="https://www.portlandoregon.gov/transportation/58929">Sunday Parkways</a> was happening around downtown &amp; Inner SE. I know, Car-Free Sundays are not sooo uncommon nowadays especially in the big western cities, but it doesn't make it any less enjoyable and delightful every time I get to be part of it.</p>
<p>Nonetheless I've participated in several Car-Free Sundays in the past in some different cities, the one in Portland felt very special and engaging - especially when the route provided me an idea of <a href="https://www.portlandoregon.gov/bps/article/654625">the Green Loop</a> - a bold new concept of the Central City 2035 Plan - that envisions a linear Park that connects several districts in downtown. It is such a great idea that people get to experience the gist of a future plan.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Sundayparkways/med/sundayparkways1.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Sundayparkways/med/sundayparkways10.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Sundayparkways/med/sundayparkways11.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Sundayparkways/med/sundayparkways3.jpg"></p>
<p>Portland's Sunday Parkways is about opening the streets back to the citizens and promote healthy active living. You can walk, bike, roll, use public transportation while participating in free public activities and events. I biked in the loop counterclockwise from the Rose Quarter to the West End to Lloyd to South Waterfront -- and stopped by countless interesting spots and stalls along the way.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Sundayparkways/med/sundayparkways6.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Sundayparkways/med/sundayparkways4.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Sundayparkways/med/sundayparkways5.jpg"></p>
<p>I used <a href="https://www.biketownpdx.com/">BikeTown</a> (which is affordable works great and!), but <a href="http://www.pdxbikerentals.com/#biketownpdx">This one</a> looks super cool too. It looks like there is a bunch of other options too - while biking on the route today I found several cycling shops with workshops/tours, cyclist organizations, and several other services that make it easier/more enjoyable to use a bicycle.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Sundayparkways/med/sundayparkways7.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Sundayparkways/med/sundayparkways8.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Sundayparkways/med/sundayparkways9.jpg"></p>
<p>I am not a bicycle expert, but I love being independent by using bikes and other forms of public transportation in Portland, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/travel/article/america-most-bike-friendly-cities/index.html">the most bike friendly city in the United States</a> and I can't wait to come back here after 2035, when the Green Loop Plan will be (hopefully) realized.</p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/portland/Sundayparkways/med/sundayparkways0.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Walk, listen, and learn - an insight from The Urbanist San Francisco tour]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/san francisco/theurbanistSF</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/san francisco/theurbanistSF</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>A few weeks ago I finally had the great opportunity to join a tour that I've been following online for a long time - <a href="http://www.theurbanistsf.com/">The Urbanist SF</a>. Of course, there are countless tours out there you can choose in a big city like San Francisco, but I'm telling you — this tour is not like the other tours, and you will see the city in a completely different way afterward. First of all, <a href="http://www.theurbanistsf.com/">The Urbanist SF</a> has a super exciting <a href="https://squareup.com/market/urbanist-sf/pedestrian-essentials-tote">Welcome to San Francisco Kit</a>, which contains some essential items for all the city lovers and urban explorers who want to discover the essence of the place.</p>
<p>What do you expect in a Welcome to San Francisco Kit? You can find a beautiful map illustrated by a local designer (I'm a map maniac and I'm quite sure that you can't find this kind of map in a regular bookstore or souvenir shops), a handmade slim wallet made out of a map, a reusable water bottle to enjoy the delicious tap water in San Francisco, delicious almond snacks from a local market... and a lot more! The kit is filled with local charm, and you can listen to the background of each item and the story of the creators while walking around the city and paying attention to the daily life of a neighborhood with Nate Mahoney, a great urbanist.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF01.jpg"><br>
<em>Nate Mahoney, the founder of The Urbanist SF</em></p>
<p>Nate Mahoney is an urbanist and UX researcher who focuses on Human-Centric design and the experience of cities.</p>
<p>Having grown up in the suburbs and traveling everywhere by car, he started to walk intensely when he made a move to San Francisco. In grad school, he encountered the concept of <em>Flâneur</em> and immediately fell in love with it. It made so much sense to him because he was already doing it — walking around the city to experience, to learn, to be... not necessarily to get point A from point B.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF03.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF04.jpg"></p>
<p>As a pedestrian, he also started talking with people — fellow pedestrians and locals — and started to look at their lives and their stories. This is how the prototype of ​​this project was born. Each item within the kit is created in collaboration with local designers and brands whom he encountered during his Flâneuring, and each item is the crystallization of their stories, their beauty.</p>
<p>I've always been fascinated by the concept of <em>Flâneur</em> — a literary concept developed by Baudelaire in 19th-century Paris. It's been my secret guide whenever I want to immerse myself in cities. Thus, it is very special to meet a fellow urbanist and flâneurian from different cities, because in my opinion they are the most tremendous guides, helping you deeply touch the texture of a city.</p>
<h3>Walking in the Mission, with special items</h3>
<p>Highlighted in an hour's tour is the Mission district, originally known as &quot;the Mission lands&quot;. San Francisco was founded on that spot by a Spanish Franciscan monk in 1776, which makes it the oldest district in San Francisco.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF05.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF06.jpg"></p>
<p>It's also famous for many artists living in the neighborhood and beautiful murals that can be found everywhere in the district. While the cost of living is relatively cheaper compared to the other partd of San Francisco, this district has not been an exception to all the urban development and gentrification. However, the district still manages to keep its local charm and dynamics.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF07.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF13.jpg"></p>
<p>Below, I will walk through some of the highlights from the tour. It all felt special, especially when I was holding the items from the kit and listening to the great stories told by Nate.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philz_Coffee">Philz coffee</a><br>
Philz coffee, opened in 2002, is an important local café that made a major contribution to the Bay Area's third wave coffee boom. They have built a very strong relationship with the local community. Currently, it expanded its brand throughout the city, but the original store in the Mission district still has an important meaning.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.sftravel.com/article/guide-san-francisco%E2%80%99s-mission-district-murals">Murals</a><br>
You can find a lot of murals at Balmy Alley, Clarion Alley, and the Women's building. If you're lucky, you can also find an artist on that spot, live painting.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF08.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF09.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF10.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF11.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF12.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF21.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF22.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF23.jpg"></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.colpapress.com/pages/about">Colpa press</a><br>
A local print shop that publishes independent magazines and books. They also have galleries and hold workshops as a platform to support local artists.<br>
I highly recommend to check out <a href="https://youtu.be/wR3PSISQy5o">Nate's interview</a> at the print shop.</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF14.jpg"></p>
<p>The illustration map contained from the Kit was printed in this print shop. It was designed by a local artist <a href="https://www.carissapotter.com/">Carissa Potter</a> and I fell in love with her project <a href="https://www.peopleiveloved.com/">People I've loved</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timbuk2">Timbuk2</a><br>
Nate's favorite! Timbuk2, a local bag brand founded in 1989, has great, high-quality products, and I enjoyed visiting their factory shop.</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF15.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF16.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF17.jpg"></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://womensbuilding.org/the-mural/">The Women’s building</a><br>
Founded in 1971, The Women's building is the first community center operated by women in San Francisco. All the exterior of the building is covered with murals.</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF28.jpg"></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mission_Dolores_Park">Dolores Park</a><br>
The final spot of the tour was Dolores Park - everyone's favorite! From this small hilly park between the Mission district and Neu Valley district, you can overlook the cityscape of San Francisco.<br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF30.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF31.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF32.jpg"></li>
</ul>
<h3>Human-centric design for cities, and the beauty of walking around</h3>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF19.jpg"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Small for such a dynamic city, San Francisco’s irreverent spirit is threaded into every neighborhood. Rich in history, the culture of San Francisco has always been a reflection of its pride, its fearlessness and its need to be seen and heard. San Francisco has a kaleidoscope of urban appeal, a place for adventure, delicacy and creature comforts. - from <a href="http://www.theurbanistsf.com/">official website</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Nate cares a lot about the experience and livability of our cities — cities for people. It takes a lot of time and effort to prepare a tour like this, because it requires a ton of research about how people live in cities and how they interact with their urban environment. The most important thing is to walk around the city and listen to the stories from people, and to discover the charm of the place and find collaborators on your own two feet. This tour teaches us that.</p>
<p>In the future, he is planning to spread this project to the other big cities in the U.S. such as Los Angeles and New York. I highly recommend The Urbanist SF to all city lovers.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF02.jpg"></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san francisco/theurbanistSF/med/theurbanistSF01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ This is not about race, but it is - thinking about white gentrification in "Black Beverly Hills"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/los angeles/BlackBeverlyHills</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/los angeles/BlackBeverlyHills</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>Recently I got to know a little bit about a neighborhood in LA called View Park, which later I discovered is called &quot;Black Beverly Hills&quot; - as opposed to its dominantly white counterpart.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/los%20angeles/BlackBeverlyHills/med/viewpark01.jpg"><br>
<em>courtesy of the California Office of Historic Preservation</em></p>
<p>Frank Ocean's song <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JDknpQzPY-o">Sweet life</a> depicts the life in &quot;the black Beverly Hills&quot; and its beauty (in this context Ladera Heights, a neighborhood that is next to View Park). Its residents are historically mostly African-American professionals - Musician Ray Charles, dancer Debbie Allen had a home in this neighborhood, just to name a few.</p>
<p>I participated <a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1907235682681593/">an event</a> during my stay in Los Angeles, which was about the new wave of gentrification in View Park that is happening right now. I thought I needed to do some research on the history of the place for deeper understanding - so here we go.</p>
<p>View Park has long been a symbol of African American success and a stronghold of black culture. According to <a href="https://la.curbed.com/2016/7/23/12254048/view-park-national-register-of-historic-places">this article</a>, the neighborhood changed dramatically after 1948, when the Supreme Court declared racial covenants unconstitutional, when white residents started moving out. By the 1980s, black residents outnumbered whites. However, the neighborhood started to change again recently.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In 2015, a group of View Park homeowners nominated the neighborhood for inclusion on the National Register of Historic Places, and as of this month, their wish was granted. However, as a Los Angeles Times feature from last July makes clear, a number of residents won’t be cheering this news, fearing the historic designation will serve as a, &quot;marketing tool to attract a new—and largely white—crop of buyers to View Park's historic homes,&quot; that will push longtime black residents out. -- Pauline O'Connor, Jul 23, 2016, Curbed</p>
</blockquote>
<h2>Gentrification, race and community value</h2>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/los%20angeles/BlackBeverlyHills/med/viewpark02.jpg"> <em>courtesy of <a href="https://ohcae.com/tag/urban/">CLARICHA EXPLAINS IT ALL</a></em></p>
<p>Gentrification is a process of renewal/revitalization of urban neighborhoods, by means of the influx of more affluent residents. Current residents are pushed out from neighborhoods in the gentrification process, because the rents and housing costs get higher - so it is linked with displacement.</p>
<p>The people who gathered to the event discussed how we can fight against displacement and keep the community value in View Park.</p>
<p>LA has a number of programs in regard to affordable housing and a set of public policies, such as <a href="https://la.curbed.com/2017/3/14/14928306/los-angeles-incentives-affordable-housing-transit-jjj">prop JJJ</a> or <a href="https://la.streetsblog.org/2018/03/02/metro-approves-equity-platform/">Metro Equity Platform Framework</a>, and they acknowledge the importance of using these resources wisely to fight against displacement.</p>
<h2>Black identity and rights</h2>
<p>While the discussion about policies for affordable housing quite was the focus of discussion there, the topic of black identity and their historical value/rights were the big part of the arguments.</p>
<p>One of the statements from the participants has quite rich implication;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;This is not about race, but it is&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When we think about who's moving in and who's moving out,where do they go and the quality of education system and social benefits - there is always a factor of race involved. Of course, we can't argue gentrification by purely the means of race and ethnicity, but it is surely part of it.</p>
<p>I'll end it here, but I'll have to keep thinking about gentrification in the whole spectrum of race, ethnicity and class - and also other political factors like gender, identity, the value of community.</p>
<p>More to read:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.latimes.com/local/la-me-adv-view-park-20150719-story.html">'Black Beverly Hills' debates historic status vs. white gentrification</a></li>
<li><a href="https://la.curbed.com/2016/7/23/12254048/view-park-national-register-of-historic-places">View Park, the Neighborhood Nicknamed 'the Black Beverly Hills,' Now on the National Register of Historic Places</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bisnow.com/los-angeles/news/neighborhood/view-park-the-black-beverly-hills-of-los-angeles-85295?utm_source=CopyShare&amp;utm_medium=Browser%5D(https://www.bisnow.com/los-angeles/news/neighborhood/view-park-the-black-beverly-hills-of-los-angeles-85295)">Residents Grapple With Change Coming To View Park, LA's 'Black Beverly Hills'</a></li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/los angeles/BlackBeverlyHills/med/viewpark01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Things to do and read for urbanists @San Francisco]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/san francisco/Introduction</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/san francisco/Introduction</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san%20francisco/Introduction/med/sanfrancisco01.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Pedro Lastra on Unsplash</em></p>
<h3>Things to do, places/project to check out</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.theurbanistsf.com/">The Urbanist SF</a> has a super exiting <a href="https://squareup.com/market/urbanist-sf/pedestrian-essentials-tote">San Francisco Kit</a>, which is everything we need to explore the city. I love the idea of having a starter kit for newcomers to the city, which is packed with all the passion/knowledge/love of the urbanist!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://womensbuilding.org/">The Women’s Building</a> is a women-led community space that advocates self-determination, gender equality and social justice. It has such a beautiful building and interesting history!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.creativegrowth.org/category/news/">Creative Growth Art Center</a> is a non-profit art center that serves artists with developmental, mental and physical disabilities. I found their office in Oakland - it's a bit far from San Francisco proper,but it might be an interesting place to visit.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3>Read</h3>
<ol start="3">
<li>
<p><a href="http://tracesf.com/">TraceSF</a> is an online journal that critically explores San Francisco Bay Area design, culture, and urbanism.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Curbed SF has great <a href="https://sf.curbed.com/maps">mapping project</a> that you can spend hours browsing!<br>
My Favorite:</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://sf.curbed.com/maps/sf-parks-private-popos-public-owned">San Francisco’s 21 best privately-owned public open spaces (POPOS)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://sf.curbed.com/maps/mapping-chinatown-history">Mapping 16 Chinatown landmarks and their history</a></li>
<li><a href="https://sf.curbed.com/maps/mapping-the-x-streets-the-city-wants-to-redesign-around-the-hub">Mapping ten crucial street redesigns around the Hub</a><br>
<a href="https://sf.curbed.com/maps/julia-morgan-buildings-best-sf">Julia Morgan's design masterpieces, mapped</a></li>
<li><a href="https://sf.curbed.com/2017/8/31/16234932/san-francisco-stereotypes-map">Offensive SF map shows what people really think of city neighborhoods</a></li>
</ul>
<ol start="5">
<li>
<p>A beautiful story about <a href="https://www.spur.org/publications/urbanist-article/2013-08-28/unbuilt-san-francisco">Unbuilt San Francisco</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://sf.streetsblog.org/">Streetblog SF</a>, a daily news source connecting people to information about sustainable transportation and livable communities.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Read <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Cool-Gray-City-Love-Francisco/dp/1608199606">Cool Gray City of Love: 49 Views of San Francisco</a>, a book with personal insights, history, reporting and analysis that portraits San Francisco.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.oldsf.org/#">OldSF</a> is a great tool for you to discover the history behind the places you see every day.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3>Organization</h3>
<ol start="7">
<li>
<p><a href="http://walksf.org/">Walk San Francisco</a> is SF's only pedestrian advocacy organization to make the city more livable, walkable.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://yimbyaction.org/">YIMBY Action (Yes in my back yard, as opposed to Not in my back yard)</a> is Empowering community stakeholders to advocate for MORE housing in the San Francisco Bay Area.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.spur.org/">SPUR</a>, San Francisco Bay Area Planning and Urban Research Association, is a leading civic planning organization to develop solutions to the big problems our cities face.</p>
</li>
</ol>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/san francisco/Introduction/med/sanfrancisco01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Hip-Hop architecture]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/los angeles/hiphoparchitecture</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/los angeles/hiphoparchitecture</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>Several days ago I got to know a brand new theory (at least for me) that is called &quot;Hip-Hop Architecture&quot; by participating an event hosted by <a href="https://www.moca.org/">MOCA</a> - The Museum of Contemporary Art, Los Angeles.</p>
<p>It featured Sekou Cooke, who is a Jamaican-born architect, researcher and a professor at Syracuse University. He has been focusing on the emergent field of hip-hop architecture.</p>
<p>I found this topic interesting and decided to write a short post about it in order to digest this still-new information for me.</p>
<h2>What is Hip-Hop Architecture?</h2>
<p>According to Sekou Cooke, <a href="http://hiphoparchitecture.com/">Hip-Hop Architecture</a> is a practice of architecture, urban planning, creative place making and economic development through the lens of hip hop culture, to create a meaningful impact on the built environment and to propose the alternatives.</p>
<p>He started his presentation by talking about Kanye West - Read <a href="https://www.archdaily.com/435952/keep-talking-kanye-an-architect-s-defense-of-kanye-west">Keep Talking Kanye: An Architect's Defense of Kanye West</a>. There are still not so many in U.S. who identify themselves both black and architect, and Kanye -as a black man, <a href="https://www.archdaily.com/893988/kanye-wests-new-architecture-venture-who-what-why-and-really">an architect</a>, and of course, a hip-hop star - is very rare and important figure. Why? Because when he talks, people listen.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Now black architects have a fighting chance at influencing the public consciousness in the way black artists, musicians, politicians and athletes have. Now the architecture of the hip-hop generation can take its rightful place alongside hip-hop music, dance, art and design. - Sekou Cooke, 2013.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Sekou Cooke's <a href="https://www.archdaily.com/894887/stop-talking-kanye-no-more-defense-for-kanye-west">defense for Kanye ended</a> eventually, but nonetheless, it's important to keep talking about hip-hop architecture itself.</p>
<h2>Practices and Hip-Hop Urbanism</h2>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/los%20angeles/hiphoparchitecture/med/hipjop02.jpg"> <em>Filip Dujardin’s ‘Fictions’ - a series of photographic plates of fictional architectural spaces. Image Courtesy of Highlight Gallery</em></p>
<p>According to this <a href="http://www.wbur.org/hereandnow/2018/06/28/hip-hop-architecture-urban-planning">article</a>, <a href="http://brandnudesign.com/">Brandnu Design</a> has started free architecture camps across the the U.S. that teach disadvantaged kids about design and urban planning through the lens of hip-hop.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;Rap has structure. The way you put together a song has a structure. And it's very easy to draw the parallel between the structure of a song and the structure of a building.&quot; Nikki Jean</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I believe this is an extremely helpful approach to invite not only kids but anyone who has been excluded from the traditional sphere of architecture and urban design and their privileged professionalism.</p>
<p>In this way, hip-hop architecture and urbanism help us to ask what kind of architecture/city and physical environment at large can be realized from the bottom up, outside of traditional strategies and approaches.</p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/los angeles/hiphoparchitecture/med/hiphop01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Arcosanti, an experimental urban laboratory and desert “utopia”]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/arcosanti/arcosanti</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/arcosanti/arcosanti</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>A few weeks ago I had a great opportunity to visit <a href="https://arcosanti.org/">Arcosanti</a> in central Arizona, 110 km north of Phoenix. It is known as an experimental town originally proposed by the Italian-American architect, Paolo Soleri (1919–2013).</p>
<h2>Soleri’s life-long pursuit of “arcology”</h2>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti01.jpg"><br>
It felt almost surreal to visit this experimental town in the middle of nowhere - our car suddenly veered off the highway and went to the unpaved gravel path. After a few minutes, a mysterious building complex emerged in front of our eyes.</p>
<p>48 years after the Soleri's first construction in 1970, this 25 acres-wide land has developed as an independent 'town' with a community of architects and urban designers who are influenced by Soleri's legacy - there are still around 80 people living in Arcosanti, actively engaging in the realization of the plan.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti02.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti03.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti04.jpg"></p>
<p>The goal of Arcosanti is to explore the concept of 'arcology' - which combines architecture and ecology - as a way to pursue the improvement of urban conditions while minimizing the destructive impact on the earth.</p>
<p>Soleri, got tired and sick of American car culture and urban sprawl (which I wholeheartedly understand), proposed to provide space for a variety of residential, commercial, and agricultural facilitieies within in the vicinity so that people can enjoy walkable urban environment while minimizing individual human environmental impact and economically self-sufficient.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti05.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti06.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti07.jpg"></p>
<h2>Living urban laboratory - still a long way to go</h2>
<p>During the tour within Arcosanti, we are informed that this desert “utopia” still attracts many curious architects, designers and artists from all over the world - even after Soleri’s alleged sexual abuse on his own daughter and the whole plan had suspended. The community currently represents over 10 nationalities. The requirement for residency includes participation on a serious of workshops and active engagement of the community. It was quite interesting to see how people live and engage with their neighbors - some of them got jobs inside of Arcosanti and some of them work outside/online. The whole community is controlled by a community council that represents the residents.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti08.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti09.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti10.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti11.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti12.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti13.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti14.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti15.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti16.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti17.jpg"></p>
<p>What I could see during my visit there is only 5% of the whole plan. Once it's completed (still 95% to go!), Arcosanti will be a dense, complex urban space that can host 5,000 people.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti30.jpg"><em>Photo by Cory Doctorow, <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/doctorow/16488755554/in/photostream/">flickr</a></em><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti31.jpg"><em>Photo by Cory Doctorow, <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/doctorow/16488755554/in/photostream/">flickr</a></em></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti18.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti19.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti20.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti21.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti22.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti23.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti24.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti25.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti26.jpg"></p>
<h2>Controversy on sexual abuse and #metoo</h2>
<p>While the idea of arcology seems amazing and the community there seems to be well-functioning, I couldn't stop thinking about <a href="https://www.dezeen.com/2017/12/18/paolo-soleri-sexual-abuse-daughter-daniela-soleri/">Soleri's sexual abuse to his own daughter</a> and its controversy. In fact, the community of Arcosanti (not Soleri himself, obviously) has their official statement for <a href="https://arcosanti.org/metoo/">#metoo</a> and it's quite interesting to see their argument on this issue.</p>
<p>With Paolo Soleri's creative intelligence and contribution to urban theory can not be denied - however, I'm still struggling whether I can appreciate an art piece no matter who created it (kind of similar argument with Wagner controversies - can we love Wagner's music even after knowing his Nazi fascination?).</p>
<p>This living urban laboratory makes us think of a lot of issues. I highly recommend a visit!</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti27.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti28.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti29.jpg"></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/arcosanti/arcosanti/med/arcosanti00.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ The urbanist’s guide to video games!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/elsewhere/Games</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/elsewhere/Games</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>Few months ago a friend of mine showed me <a href="https://ncase.me/polygons/">a very interesting website</a> that blew my mind — Parable of Polygons: an playable post on the shape of society. It shows a simulation of segregation that is playfully designed to make it easier for readers to understand. This website is based off the work of Nobel Prize-winning game theorist Thomas Schelling and his 1971 paper on dynamic models of segregation.</p>
<p>By letting you play with their simulation and explaining the theory step by step along with it, it walks you through how a small demand for diversity can desegregate a neighborhood. I realized how much it helps me to understand the rhetoric if I get to be ‘involved’ and actively being part of a process.</p>
<p>This leads me to the beauty of playability in the field of games, especially video games. The authors of the website were inspired by Ian Bogost’s book <a href="http://bogost.com/books/persuasive_games/">Persuasive Games: The Expressive Power of Videogames</a> and I, inspired, decided to read it.</p>
<h2><strong>Why video games are not as bad as we think</strong></h2>
<p>This book is an analysis of how video games can influence players, even their fundamental attitudes and beliefs about the world.</p>
<p>Of course, video games have suffered from a negative social connotation and are often not taken seriously.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Despite their commercial success, video games still struggle for acceptance as a cultural form. They are perceived to serve no cultural or social function save distraction at best, moral baseness at worst. (Bogost, 2010, p15)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>However, according to this book, video games can be a great storytelling medium that have significant impact on players (if they're used well, of course).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I’m saying that this is a mature storytelling medium that has enormous power to shape the debates within our culture. (…) this book suggests that video games open a new domain for persuasion, thanks to their core representational mode, procedurally.(…) I call this new form procedural rhetoric, the art of persuasion through rule-based representations and interactions rather than the spoken word, writing, images, or moving pictures. (Bogost, 2010, p21)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>With that in mind, I started digging into the games that have a close relationship with the fields of urban design and architecture. Some of them are amazing tools for urban simulation or education, and even for citizen participation.</p>
<p>Here are three video games I have been playing and loving so far.</p>
<h2>Video games that are great for city lovers</h2>
<h3>1. Block’hood</h3>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*eFwmbDY3I9wIF63Z.jpg" alt="Photo from the official website: https://www.plethora-project.com/blockhood/"><em>Photo from the official website: <a href="https://www.plethora-project.com/blockhood/">https://www.plethora-project.com/blockhood/</a></em></p>
<p>I only started to play <a href="https://www.plethora-project.com/blockhood/">Block’hood</a> recently but this city building simulator video game hasn’t let me down so far. You get to build a city vertically and experience the unique ecosystems within. If you play in story mode, it walks you through the basic principles of urban design (such as connectivity, energy sufficiency, necessary resources and so on) and I think it’s quite helpful for educational purposes.</p>
<h3>2. Cities: Skylines</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.paradoxplaza.com/cities-skylines/CSCS00GSK-MASTER.html">Cities: Skylines</a> is my absolute favorite. I love this TED talk shown below as much as I do the game itself. It is a quite advanced and realistic game and I’m quite sure that you'll need to use your urban planning knowledge to succeed.</p>
<iframe src="https://embed.ted.com/talks/lang/en/karoliina_korppoo_how_a_video_game_might_help_us_build_better_cities" width="854" height="480" style="position:absolute;left:0;top:0;width:100%;height:100%" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>It's also quite fun to look at all the imaginary cities created by other players, and get to know how/why they built it and how it works in the game.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/elsewhere/Games/med/game01.jpg"><em>Photo from Steam</em><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/elsewhere/Games/med/game02.jpg"><em>Photo from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9xj4ciP0Riw">Cities:Skylines Review</a></em></p>
<h3>3. Block by Block (Minecraft)</h3>
<p>Minecraft is an older, famous video game, but what I want to highlight is not Minecraft itself but the initiative called <a href="https://blockbyblock.org/">Block by Block</a>. Block by Block uses Minecraft to engage with challenged communities through a range of workshops, and raises funds for implementation of public spaces.</p>
<p>I mean, it’s a super easy and fun game and you can create anything by hand — it’s a brilliant idea to use Minecraft to encourage citizen participation, and to raise awareness that everyone, including non-professionals, can and <em>should</em> engage in our cities and public spaces.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*0tpzhR-cNmhy-bau.jpg" alt="Photo from the official website: Block by Block"><em>Photo from the official website: <a href="https://blockbyblock.org/">Block by Block</a></em></p>
<p>Thanks for reading and please contact me if you have any recommendations!</p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/elsewhere/Games/med/game03.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Things to do and read for urbanists @Los Angeles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/los angeles/Introduction</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/los angeles/Introduction</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/los%20angeles/Introduction/med/losangeles02.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Jack Finnigan on Unsplash</em></p>
<h3>Things to do, places/project to check out</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Downtown Los Angeles's <a href="http://downtownartwalk.org/">Art Walk</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A public program that lets people to build a community parklet easily: <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/3026002/diy-kits-to-help-build-your-own-mini-park-anywhere-there-is-space-on-the-street?partner=rss">People St program</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A 10-year economic development and revitalization initiative to get an identity back to the city. <a href="https://bringingbackbroadway.com/">Bringing Back Broadway</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>An interesting project that brought the nature back to the former-industrial, challenged area. <a href="https://www.laparks.org/reccenter/augustus-f-hawkins-natural">Augustus F. Hawkins natural park</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Famous art spaces like <a href="https://www.hauserwirth.com/locations/10069-hauser-wirth-los-angeles">HAUSER &amp; WIRTH</a> and <a href="https://artsharela.org/">Art Share L.A.</a> are also worth visiting.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>18 places in LA where black architects left their mark - <a href="https://la.curbed.com/maps/los-angeles-black-architects-projects-map">this</a> is a ultimate list and mapping.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A world-renowned independent architecture schools, and it often has exhibition that is open to the public. <a href="https://sciarc.edu/events/exhibitions">GALLERIES AT SCI-ARC</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A famous architecture designed by Frank Lloyd Wright - <a href="https://buy.acmeticketing.com/events/335/list">Hollyhock House</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A residential dwelling design by Frank Lloyd Wright - <a href="http://ennishouse.com/">Ennis House</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3>Read</h3>
<ol start="10">
<li>
<p>I found this beautiful book at a book store in Art Share L.A.:<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sidewalking-Coming-Terms-Los-Angeles/dp/0520273729/ref=la_B001HD3GQO_1_6?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1530294824&amp;sr=1-6">Sidewalking: Coming to Terms with Los Angeles</a> written by David L. Ulin - it is his journey of trying to 'make sense' of the city. His another book of L.A. looks equaly interesting too: <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Writing-Los-Angeles-Anthology-Publication/dp/1931082278">Writing Los Angeles: A Literary Anthology</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Get to know the overall picture of <a href="https://www.planetizen.com/tag/los-angeles">what is happening in LA</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Very helpful <a href="http://planning.lacity.org/urbandesign/resources/DowntownDesignGuide.php">resources</a> to understand urban design principals in LA</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I spent hours to check out Curbed's all <a href="https://la.curbed.com/maps">mapping projects</a> - it's a great way to get to know LA from various perspective. Especially these urban-renewal related mapping projects are helpful to check a slew of new developments that's is coming/happening to some neighborhood.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://la.curbed.com/maps/westlake-development-hotels-mixed-use-construction">Mapping the changes on Westlake’s horizon</a></li>
<li><a href="https://la.curbed.com/maps/chinatown-development-gentrification-map">Changes underway in Chinatown, mapped</a></li>
<li><a href="https://la.curbed.com/maps/arts-district-los-angeles-development-map-2">Mapping the Arts District's never-ending parade of development</a></li>
</ul>
<ol start="14">
<li>
<p>Watch <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinatown_(1974_film)">Chinatown</a> (1974) and read <a href="http://www.laweekly.com/arts/chinatown-is-the-story-of-white-supremacy-and-gentrification-in-la-8333951">this</a> interesting article about the movie, arguing about white supremacy and gentrification in L.A.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Activist and journalist Alissa Walker's <a href="http://www.awalkerinla.com/">blog</a> is a great introduction to the city and it makes wanna walk L.A.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3>Organization</h3>
<ol start="15">
<li>
<p><a href="http://skidrow.org/">Skid Row Housing Trust</a> is a great initiative that provides permanent supportive housing for people who need supports. For those who are not familiar with Skid Row area, watch this short <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vTJWdtX90C0">documentary</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://doartfoundation.org/">Do ArT Foundation</a>, a non-profit social enterprise created to produce publicArt programs, projects and exhibitions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://laforum.org/">L.A. Forum for Architecture and Urban Design</a> is an independent nonprofit organization and organizes public programming, exhibitions, and publications. I went to one of their event &quot;<a href="http://laforum.org/event/adu-2-0-transforming-the-city-from-inside-out-l-a-taipei-city/">TRANSFORMING THE CITY FROM INSIDE OUT // L.A. &amp; TAIPEI CITY</a>&quot; and it was quite interesting.</p>
</li>
</ol>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/los angeles/Introduction/med/losangeles02.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Things to do and read for urbanists @Tokyo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/Introduction</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/Introduction</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/tokyo/Introduction/med/tokyo01.jpg"><br>
<em>Photo by Andre Benz on Unsplash</em></p>
<h3>Things to do, places/project to check out</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Participate <a href="http://urbaning.org/u/">URBANING_U</a> which is a two day camp, that let you learn more about Tokyo thorough urbanist's perspective.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you're an cyclist and want to experience biking in Tokyo, I absolutely recommend <a href="https://flipboard.com/@byronkidd/tokyo-by-bike-2gjbbsugy">TOKYO BY BIKE</a> - this is a very helpful introduction to Japan's bike scene.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I love the art center <a href="http://www.ongoing.jp/ja/artcenter/index.php">ongoing</a>, which is a special art space / gallery that is very accessible to any artists, including un-famous, fledgling ones.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Read</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Follow <a href="http://beingtokyo.com/">BeingTokyo</a>, which is a rotation curation account on Twitter.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Check out the books by <a href="http://www.flickstudio.jp/index.html">Flick Studio</a>, which is a publishing company specialized in Architecture and urban design.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I like watching NHK's project <a href="http://www.nhk.or.jp/special/tmc/">Tokyo Miracle City</a> - fragments of everyday lives by Tokyoists.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Organization</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="http://mi-ri.com/">mi-rimeter</a> is a great team that practice bottom-up urban intervention and tactical urbanism. They also have a <a href="http://urbaning.jp/">design farm</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://shibuyahack.com/">Shibuya Hack Project</a> believes in the citizen's power and right to cities.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/1546778725440736/">Urbanist Meetup</a> is an online community of people who love city, architecture, urban design, real estate and community development.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you love gardening, you'd love <a href="https://tokyogreenspace.com/tag/tokyo-diy-gardening/">Tokyo Green Space</a> andthis facebook community <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/urbanfarmingtokyo/">Urban Farming Tokyo</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/tokyo/Introduction/med/tokyo01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Seaholm EcoDistrict - Austin's sustainable urban renewal]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/austin/Seaholm_EcoDistrict</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/austin/Seaholm_EcoDistrict</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>Seaholm EcoDistrict is an 85-acre urban development on the edge of downtown - it once used to be the city-owned power plant and a water treatment facility. After the power plant was decommissioned in 1989, a new public-private partnership was formed to renew this part of downtown by using green, sustainable design.</p>
<p>Seaholm EcoDistrict looks quite relaxed and surprisingly walkable (even within the heat!), with a vibrant hub of residential, office, and community gathering spaces.</p>
<p>It is quite interesting to see an environmentally considerate project like Seaholm EcoDistrict in Texas, where car ownership and private property are close to a religion.</p>
<p>You can easily access there from the new central library (which is also worth a visit) if you want to see how Austin's sustainable green urban renewal looks like. You can chill at one of their public chairs, or it's ok to charge your phone for free at one of the solar-panel installed benches.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Seaholm_EcoDistrict/med/Seaholm01.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Seaholm_EcoDistrict/med/Seaholm02.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Seaholm_EcoDistrict/med/Seaholm03.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Seaholm_EcoDistrict/med/Seaholm04.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Seaholm_EcoDistrict/med/Seaholm05.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Seaholm_EcoDistrict/med/Seaholm06.jpg"></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Seaholm_EcoDistrict/med/Seaholm01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Mueller - a former industrial zone to a sustainable enclave]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/austin/Mueller</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/austin/Mueller</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<h2>Mueller doesn't look like anywhere else in Austin</h2>
<p>During my stay in Austin, I had a chance to visit a neighborhood called Mueller - Austin's 700-acre wide 'showplace' of new urbanism and enlightened sustainable living.</p>
<p>The neighborhood looks lovely, with the beautifully designed houses and green street trees etc. It is hard to believe that this area used to be an industrial site not so long time ago - it was an outdated municipal airport, which closed in 1999.</p>
<p>Now it turned into a vibrant neighborhood, with the residential houses and shops, open space and parks, communal summing pools and other necessary facilities. This is a city's effort to bring new residents into the central part of Austin to this greener, more sustainable neighborhood.</p>
<h2>Austin as “carbon neutral”city</h2>
<p>In recent years, many cities are pledging to become “carbon neutral” by 2050 - Austin, where car ownership and car-dependent lifestyle seem to be still highly valued, is not the exception. According to <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/urban-expeditions/austin/austin-green-buildings-fight-urban-sprawl/">this article</a>, Austin adopted a new legislation to make&quot;all new homes are to be rated net-zero capable, meaning they produce as much electricity as they consume.&quot;</p>
<p>Mueller is one of the pioneers of this green buildings movement, aiming to invite the residents back to the city core to live in the sustainable, eco-friendly designed neighborhood.</p>
<p>Of course, there is a downside too - once a low-income industrial neighborhood, the prices and development have increased rapidly in recent years. According to this well-written article, a market study showed a shortage of nearly 50,000 affordable apartments in 2014.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Mueller/med/Meuller01.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Mueller/med/Meuller02.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Mueller/med/Meuller03.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Mueller/med/Meuller04.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Mueller/med/DSC09673.jpg"></p>
<h2>On racial diversity and 'a meaningful community'</h2>
<p>Aside from the gentrification issue, it's easy to praise this neighborhood - sustainable, well maintained and functioning central city neighborhood. However, Mueller also struggles with other urban problems like the other neighborhoods in the city.I found <a href="https://www.npr.org/2015/02/13/385495327/a-community-takes-on-racial-tensions-once-hidden-under-the-surface">the article</a> that talks about the racial tension of Mueller and I found it more interesting.</p>
<p>Mueller is created based on the idea of &quot;new urbanism&quot;, in which a meaningful community plays a great rule. However, there have been some issues with African-American residents who don't feel so welcomed in this neighborhood.</p>
<p>It is quite interesting to know that Austin is one of the nation's fastest-growing metropolis but the only fast-growing city in America with a declining black population (University of Texas report). According to <a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2014/07/18/african-american-austin/">this report</a>, Austin's general population jumped 20 percent from 2000 to 2010, but the number of African-Americans shrank by 5 percent.</p>
<p>Racial tension and everyday racism are of course not limited in Mueller, but while walking around this beautiful neighborhood, I couldn't stop but thinking what 'a meaningful community' is about and how we can create one in our cities in diversity.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Mueller/med/DSC09674.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Mueller/med/DSC09676.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Mueller/med/DSC09682.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Mueller/med/DSC09685.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Mueller/med/DSC09689.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Mueller/med/DSC09692.jpg"></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Mueller/med/Meuller01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Austin Creative Reuse]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/austin/CreativeReuse</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/austin/CreativeReuse</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bnr5nmwKq-Y" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>I found this little place called <a href="https://austincreativereuse.org/">Austin Creative Reuse</a>, which is run by a nonprofit organization that collects, sells, and distributes donated articles. They focus on a community building for smarter purchase and consumption decisions.</p>
<p>They've got everything - from old playing cards to used textiles - and you can get almost everything under 1$. It's not the affordable price that makes this place special and fun though - what's fun for me is the fact that I could see the random 'materials' and texture of the city in this place.</p>
<p>All the used objects that are collected by the locals tell a lot about the previous owners, their tastes and trends of that time. It is also fun to see how these objects are creatively reused by school children and artists etc.</p>
<p>I highly recommend a visit!</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/CreativeReuse/med/CreativeReuse01.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/CreativeReuse/med/CreativeReuse02.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/CreativeReuse/med/CreativeReuse03.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/CreativeReuse/med/CreativeReuse04.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/CreativeReuse/med/CreativeReuse05.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/CreativeReuse/med/CreativeReuse06.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/CreativeReuse/med/CreativeReuse07.jpg"><br>
<img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/CreativeReuse/med/CreativeReuse08.jpg"></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/CreativeReuse/med/CreativeReuse01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Urbanism-Related Things to do and read @Austin]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/austin/Introduction</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/austin/Introduction</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Introduction/med/Austin01.jpeg"></p>
<h3>Things to do, places to go</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Austin’s “new urbanist enclave”, <a href="http://www.muelleraustin.com/">Mueller</a><br>
Read: <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/environment/urban-expeditions/austin/austin-green-buildings-fight-urban-sprawl/">How One City Turned Industrial Zones Into Green Enclaves</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fostering conservation and reuse through creativity, education and community building. There are also some volunteer opportunities available for all! — <a href="https://austincreativereuse.org/">Austin Creative Reuse</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>creative hub for DIY crafting, workshops, and events. — <a href="http://madeatcraft.com/">CRAFT</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Hack the commute by using bicycle and other alternative transportation in this very car-centric city. - <a href="https://austinbcycle.com/">AustinBcycle</a> and <a href="https://www.bird.co/">Bird Scooters</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3>Read</h3>
<ol start="5">
<li>
<p>For the better understanding of the political dimension of Austin’s urbanism — <a href="https://medium.com/@andrewdobbs?source=post_header_lockup">Andrew Dobbs</a>, Activist, organizer, and writer based in Austin, Texas.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Get a general view of the city — <a href="https://opportunityurbanism.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/TheTexasWayOfUrbanismReport-8.pdf">The Texas way of Urbanism</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>On racial diversity:<br>
・<a href="https://www.planetizen.com/node/73812">Does New Urbanism Have a Racial Problem?</a><br>
・<a href="https://www.npr.org/2015/02/12/385474414/with-porches-and-parks-a-texas-community-aims-for-urban-utopia">With Porches And Parks, A Texas Community Aims For Urban Utopia</a><br>
・<a href="https://www.npr.org/2015/02/13/385495327/a-community-takes-on-racial-tensions-once-hidden-under-the-surface">A Texas Community Takes On Racial Tensions Once Hidden Under The Surface</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://austin.bibliocommons.com/list/show/128108121/1131292877">Great book recommendation</a> to know more about the history and identity of Austin by The librarians at Austin Public.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3>Organization</h3>
<ol start="9">
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.open-austin.org/about/">Open Austin</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.centraltexascnu.org/about-cnu-central-texas/">CNU Central Texas</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The voice for this region’s architecture community — <a href="https://www.aiaaustin.org/about">AIA Austin</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A partnership of downtown property owners, individuals, and businesses devoted to preserving and enhancing the value and vitality of downtown Austin. — <a href="http://www.downtownaustin.com/daa/about-us">The Downtown Austin Alliance</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Central Texas’ first and only Transportation Management Association. - <a href="http://movabilityaustin.org/">Movability</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/AustinPermacultureGuild/">Austin Permaculture Grid</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Foralternative transportation and smart trips, check out <a href="https://bikeaustin.org/">Bike Austin</a> and<a href="http://smarttripsaustin.org/">Smart Trips Austin</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/austin/Introduction/med/Austin01.jpeg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ 9 beautiful books on urban analysis and research]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/elsewhere/Books</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/elsewhere/Books</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>There are many great books out there on urban planning and design, but I realized not many of them quite sum up the full scope of roles of urban analysis and research. I believe that analytical process to make sense of our cities itself is a creative act, which has a power to give us the different ways of perceiving our urban surroundings.</p>
<p>Here are my 9 favorite books that show you the beauty of getting deeper knowledge of your city. Each of them have their own unique perspectives and methodologies to approach the urban realities (or non-realities), and they all invite you to observe your cities with different angles, rather than ‘teaching’ what they are.</p>
<h2>1. Tokyo Totem</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*6q2Ooe_1RXRFa6slIUnvxQ.png" alt="More about Tokyo Totem"><em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Tokyo-Totem-Guide-English-Japanese/dp/4904894286/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1526722018&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=tokyo+totem">More about Tokyo Totem</a></em></p>
<p>It was created by Amsterdam-based research lab Monnik, based on the workshop they did while staying Tokyo .Tokyo Totem is an ultimate subjective guide to Tokyo — it doesn't tell you where to go and what to see (like Lonely Planet), but rather, gives you an idea of “how” to see, and experience Tokyo in your personal way, and make it your own.</p>
<h2>2. FARE MAGAZINE</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*lDN4SLFFG-WD2rXkuNRdIg.png" alt="More about FARE"><em><a href="https://www.faremag.com/">More about FARE</a></em></p>
<p>Fare is all about food and cities! It’s it the best combination? Each issue focuses on one specific city, and by telling the immersive stories of its food and local culture, it explores and discovers the complexity and richness of the neighborhoods.</p>
<h2>3. Measuring The Non-measurable 06: Subjectivities In Investigation Of The Urban</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/3200/1*jGYG-qwx7aPsMm2xfTiATQ.png" alt="More about this book"><em><a href="https://www.amazon.co.jp/Subjectivities-Investigation-Urban-%E9%83%BD%E5%B8%82%E3%81%AE%E6%8E%A2%E6%B1%82%E3%81%AB%E3%81%8A%E3%81%91%E3%82%8B%E4%B8%BB%E8%A6%B3%E6%80%A7%E3%80%9C%E5%8F%AB%E3%81%B3%E3%81%A8%E5%BD%B1%E3%81%A8%E9%8F%A1%E5%83%8F-Non-Measurable/dp/4904894162/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1526722331&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=Measuring+The+Non-measurable+06%3A+Subjectivities+In+Investigation+Of+The%C2%A0Urban">More about this book</a></em></p>
<p>Darko Radovic is one of the best urban researchers I know, who is a professor of Architecture and Urban Design at Keio University, an initiator and a founding co-Director of International Keio Institute for Architecture and Urbanism. This book contains the research output from three cities, Tokyo, Bangkok and Singapore by his student, which beautifully depicts the urban texture of each city.</p>
<h2>4. Migropolis</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*Y1f65WmHej5VJcKeYJOeww.png" alt="More about Migropolis"><em><a href="http://cargocollective.com/monnik/Beyroutes">More about Migropolis</a></em></p>
<p>Incredibly thick and rich analysis and archive of Venice, as the prototypical city confronting the forces of globalization and mobility in the 21st century. You can get drunk by the tens of thousands of photographs, case studies, movement profiles and statistic data in this book!</p>
<h2>5. City Tales series by Helen Constantine</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*9k7d4ddSh-NLF_0zqZWYZQ.png" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*OWe2PWHrv5Lb90CXfRZVlg.png" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*u-DkkUtRQ5V58TOK9qkLhA.png" alt="More about the City Tales"><em><a href="https://global.oup.com/academic/content/series/c/city-tales-cta/?cc=us&amp;lang=en&amp;">More about the City Tales</a></em></p>
<p>An editor Helen Constantine from Oxford press published a series of the collections of short stories about cities. Each stories from a different century and genre is set in a specific city, and after reading an entire stories from a book, I bet you feel like you just traveled the city from corners to corners, from time to time.</p>
<h2>6. MONU</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*24Xl5-u2fRGMcD08OQ-x_Q.png" alt="More about MONU"><em><a href="http://www.monu-magazine.com/issues.htm">More about MONU</a></em></p>
<p>MONU is a magazine on urbanism and I love their unique perspective — such as ‘interior urbanism’ and ‘decentralized urbanism’. Their comparative analysis helps us to make sense of our cities from a variety of perspectives.</p>
<h2>7. From here to there</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*0IHAhcdmXyRhmvWex3GDHg.png" alt="More about From here to there"><em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Here-There-Curious-Collection-Association/dp/1568988826">More about From here to there</a></em></p>
<p>A Curious Collection from the Hand Drawn Map Association, and it’s all about maps! The interesting thing about a hand draw map is that it always delivers a writer’s subjective spacial understanding. The book is not exactly focused on research or analysis, but it surely makes you explore the hundreds of differently ways of understanding space/place.</p>
<h2>8. BEIRUT</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*frKSDgnIB8igXAj9SPcHpg.png" alt="More about the book"><em><a href="http://www.monnik.org/tag/beirut/">More about the book</a></em></p>
<p>Presented by Monnik, an Amsterdam-based research lab (same as Tokyo Totem). This book also doesn’t quite tell you its sightseeing spots and places to eat, but after reading it, you can feel like you just finished a very long/deep conversation with locals — and understand the city in a unique way.</p>
<h2>9. 思考都市 — A city of thinking</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*u4kFd1iFUbOVD_zPNq-S2A.png" alt="More about the book"><em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/%E6%80%9D%E8%80%83%E9%83%BD%E5%B8%82-%E5%9D%82%E5%8F%A3%E6%81%AD%E5%B9%B3-Drawings-1999-2012/dp/4528010569/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1526723236&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=%E6%80%9D%E8%80%83%E9%83%BD%E5%B8%82">More about the book</a></em></p>
<p>This book is available only in Japanese at the moment, but dozens of detailed illustrations by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kyohei_Sakaguchi">Kyohei Sakaguchi</a> is definitely worth checking. Most of them are the sketches from his fieldwork on homeless people living in Tokyo.</p>
<hr>
<p>Intrigued?</p>
<p>Last but not least, I recently came across <a href="http://radlab.info/">RAD</a> (Research for Architecture Domain), Japanese collaborative research-based practices, and I love what one of the co-founder Kawakatsu says at<a href="https://www.domusweb.it/en/architecture/2012/11/07/studio-visit-02-research-for-architecture-domain.html"> DOMUS</a>;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>we specifically think of research as a performative act that always operates in connection to practice. Although it may at times be similar, we do not position the research as being academic, nor as a preliminary step for making something. What is important is that it is inductive, engaged with the field, and evidential.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Let me know your recommendation as well!</p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/elsewhere/Books/med/Book01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ What I learned at “Renovation School” in Tokyo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/renovationschooltokyo</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/renovationschooltokyo</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/tokyo/renovationschooltokyo/med/Renovationschool01.jpg"></p>
<p>Have you ever heard of the “Renovation School” in Japan?</p>
<p>You might already know that Japan is experiencing a rapid degeneration due to the declining population. This decline raises a lot of social issues such as daycare, taxation and a critical labor shortage — and remarkably the increasing number of vacant homes, stores and abandoned infrastructure is part of the problem we are facing.</p>
<p>In recent years, people have gradually started to realize that not using these vacant buildings in order to create something valuable for their communities is a waste. This is the reason why renovation is becoming increasingly popular as a way of urban intervention. It is an act of appreciating what we already have, and updating it to add new value so that it can fit the needs of our contemporary life and future.</p>
<h2><strong>What is the “renovation school” in Japan?</strong></h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*F6PbXBfZ7E7dxPww99XMVw.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>The Renovation School, originally started in Kyushu in 2011, is a d/4 days “place of practice” into which participants are divided into small units and come up with action plans to reuse the targeted vacant houses. Participants also need to think about business models to make the plans realistic and feasible. At the end, the participants then propose these plans to the real estate owners, aiming to bring these plans to fruition after school. Although it is called “school”, it’s not about the “learning”, but rather the “doing”.</p>
<p>I heard about this movement when I lived in Copenhagen, and I’d been wanting to be part of it ever since. In 2017, I finally had an opportunity to participate in a 3-day Renovation School, which at this time focused on the Ikegami area, the south part of Tokyo. The school was under the sponsorship of the Tokyu Corporation — one of the major private railway companies and land developers in Japan — which I found it a little ironic, but I’ll talk more about that later in this post.</p>
<p>In this blog post, I try to explain what Renovation School in Japan is like, and how it (even though they never really articulate it as it is) uses a great design sprint method within the 3 days. I hope it also helps you understand a little bit where Japanese urbanism is heading.</p>
<h2><strong>3 day design sprint to come up with the future of abandoned buildings in Tokyo</strong></h2>
<p>At the beginning of the School, participants (by the way, even though it’s called “school”, most of us were not students but full time workers) were divided into small teams. Each team got to meet a house owner who owns a vacant building — they don’t know what to do with it. Our mission is to come up with a renovation plan and business model for that vacant building in order to give it a new life. I will quickly summarise what we have done in 3 days at the Renovation School.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2048/1*FTdpAiaS5TSc8OZtlSXeAQ.jpeg" alt="Day 1: UNDERSTANDING — Area Analysis &amp; Field work"><em>Day 1: UNDERSTANDING — Area Analysis &amp; Field work</em></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*Z_y6229J5g_nQ85ST3hyaA.jpeg" alt="This little building was our team’s assignment"><em>This little building was our team’s assignment</em></p>
<p>The first day is all about input and developing an understanding of the area — these buildings are empty for a reason, right? It’s not like we can make WHATEVER in WHENEVER. No one wants to build a Disneyland in the middle of nowhere. If we don’t create shared knowledge and explore the problem from all angles under a shared brain, it’s extremely difficult to come up with a realistic plan — that’s why this first day of understanding is crucial during the Renovation School, we were told.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*q22-7jUckq3_ZNrTwgB56Q.jpeg" alt="Doing an interview with a local shop owner"><em>Doing an interview with a local shop owner</em></p>
<p>This time’s focus area is called Ikegami, which is known as the last stop of the Tokyu Ikegami railway Line. The area has attracted many people since ancient times, as it is part of the path to the famous Ikegami Honmonji Temple. However, Ikegami is not an exception to the sad Japanese urban reality, that faces the population decline and the rising rate of vacancy.</p>
<p>We spend the first day doing field work and intense desktop analysis, observing the people in the area and physical environment, as well as gathering data such as demography and learning about histories. We also conducted a lot of interviews with shop owners around our targeted vacant buildings.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*hLA_osE-ydxA9lfR-9e-ag.jpeg" alt="Day 2: SKETCH &amp; DECIDE — Brainstorming &amp; Synthesis / Idea Sketch"><em>Day 2: SKETCH &amp; DECIDE — Brainstorming &amp; Synthesis / Idea Sketch</em></p>
<p>We gathered the memos of interviews, new findings obtained from field work,documents/materials to explain the history, demographic data etc — time for synthesis. The question to be asked is, of course, what is needed in this place? We had an intense brainstorming session to come up with the solicitations and we chose which ideas should be prototyped.</p>
<p>Although there were countless ideas to reuse the vacant houses — such as making it a coworking space, cafe, private residence, etc…, it is likely that some of these ideas just don’t quite fit in certain places. We also need to think about the users and stakeholders, management and management systems too!</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2048/1*2FbZ5bN0u3ysuySqnY05iw.jpeg" alt="Day 3: PROTOTYPE AND VALIDATE"><em>Day 3: PROTOTYPE AND VALIDATE</em></p>
<p>Finally we presented our idea in front of the building owners, landowner and developer, and of course, the locals and see how they interact with our ideas and get direct feedback from the target audience. Even though we had a great idea, we knew that the presentation for them is as important as coming up with solution ideas themselves — otherwise, who will give our ideas a chance?</p>
<p>That was a rough summary of what we did during the 3 days, and below, I will share the three things that I learned from the renovation school.</p>
<h2>1. Always think about the actual actors — we don’t need “faceless” proposals anymore</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*LlqstS4qGEzywR2mQx1Kfw.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>The purpose of the renovation school is to make the ACTION plan, not the proposal itself. That is why the business model and the feasibility of the management system are quite important — otherwise, what’s the point of having a proposal?</p>
<p>Our team members were full of ideas — renovating an empty building into a community center and inviting more people / would be amazing to have an bar inside so that people could gather and chill.But, then, who can proceed? When the question was returned, silence often spreads fast.</p>
<p>When the question “who will do it?” remains ambiguous, only ideas are kept scattered, and at the end of all the good ideas just melt into air. It is necessary to thoroughly discuss the proposals that you really want to realize, a proposal that specifies actual actors.</p>
<p>….but of course, it doesn’t mean that we can’t “dream” about all the nonsense.</p>
<h2><strong>2. The importance of interdisciplinality</strong></h2>
<p>Traditionally, specific experts such as urban planning experts, architects, real estate agents and developers have stipulated the way the city is. However, as society became more complicated nowadays, our citizens are responsible for the way the town is. I believe it is through interdisciplinary cooperation that we can unbind ourselves from the framework of specialised fields. I always find it very suggestive that Jane Jacobs is neither an architect nor an academic researcher.</p>
<p>The second thing I learned at the renovation school was exactly this interdisciplinary collaboration. In my team (there were 9 of us in total), there was a designer, banker (!), architects, researcher, and media expert as well as a public officials, all different genders and ages. Everybody had different background and beliefs, and for that reason, there were some moments of conflicts and disagreement, I wouldn’t say it was easy — but isn’t this “chaos” itself is what we have in cities?</p>
<h2>3. Tell the “story” of a place</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*-ajaFFE61gXQgzQC4qrGUQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*glF4I-KZbVvqVXdMrfuseA.jpeg" alt="I love these small details of everyday life inTokyo"><em>I love these small details of everyday life inTokyo</em></p>
<p>In the Renovation School, as mentioned above, each team gets one existing empty house/building to work on a proposal for. I was taught at the school that we need to add “personality” or, let’s say, “story” to the place, instead of calling it a property — which sounds too static and impersonal.</p>
<p>If there is no concept or a story that people can sympathise with, as a place where there is nothing to be changed anywhere, new values ​​and the like are not born from there. If you want to create a place that you want to carry your feet, you should scoop out features like characters and characters that stand out from that place and languages ​​together with stories that everyone can sympathise.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*X_6eTYhXJiEi2zl30Pgx_A.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>So…after those intense 3 days, I still ask myself — what is my role in making cities more livable and sustainable? What will happen to Japanese cities in the future? Even though the rate of vacant houses are still rising, most of the big developers in Japan, including Tokyu-Corporation (the organizer of the renovation school for this time), keep constructing new fancy buildings for urban redevelopment. I see an irony here. After spending 3 days of very intense design sprint, I couldn’t stop but hope to see more of those collective actions in Japan, especially NOW when urban development is booming before the Tokyo Olympic Games in 2020.</p>
<p>Let’s just hope that these new urban movements, such as the Renovation School, could shift the direction of Japanese urban development a little bit towards a better tommorow.</p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/tokyo/renovationschooltokyo/med/Renovationschool01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Event report: “Hack My City” — Connecting the Urban Scales from XS to XL]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/HackMyCity</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/HackMyCity</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>In March 2018, some of my colleagues and I had an opportunity to invite some of the most prominent practitioners in the field of urban community planning in Japan to our one-day event “Hack my City”.</p>
<p>The event was hosted by<a href="http://shibuyahack.com/"> Shibuya Hack Project</a> and the theme of the day was “from XS to XL — the methodology of urban development to think across the scales”.</p>
<p>Shibuya Hack Project is a bottom-up urban initiative in Shibuya that uses the methodology of tactical urbanism, encouraging the citizens to “own” the city and use the urban space freely. This is an attempt to give a long-term effect ( XL) in a short-term small practice (XS).</p>
<p>The project has been doing various activities since 2013,from<a href="http://shibuyahack.com/2017/07/streetfurnitureinchuogai/"> making street furniture</a> to<a href="http://shibuyahack.com/2018/02/ese_shibuya_exhibition/"> organising an art exhibition</a> ; however, there has been a clear distance between it and the mainstream urban regeneration that is happening in Shibuya.</p>
<p>Thus, we wanted to tackle the question of how we can connect the small-scaled bottom-up citizen initiatives with large-scale urban developments, which tend to leave the grassroots initiatives behind. It also involves the question of how we can make sense of the distance between our everyday lives and actions and the meta-scaled narrative and representation of Tokyo.</p>
<p>This post briefly covers the discussion we had that day.</p>
<p>※<em>This post is based on:<a href="https://l.messenger.com/l.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Floftwork.com%2Fjp%2Fevent%2F20180313_hmc_report&amp;h=ATMB4AWkQqiqV6gUJLAJMpUWFMIkYB1JcKAdPhFCdrdxKIaCj31JlPZ4DgYwSoJSOTv8jeAnNRo3MM2KX-oG1Ij5SHuC9c6jVmXL_Pe8f7gxj6HjMcFW_w3hLh8"> https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report</a></em></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*IEAJ4RS-SlSJcmKu.jpg" alt="https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report"><em><a href="https://l.messenger.com/l.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Floftwork.com%2Fjp%2Fevent%2F20180313_hmc_report&amp;h=ATMB4AWkQqiqV6gUJLAJMpUWFMIkYB1JcKAdPhFCdrdxKIaCj31JlPZ4DgYwSoJSOTv8jeAnNRo3MM2KX-oG1Ij5SHuC9c6jVmXL_Pe8f7gxj6HjMcFW_w3hLh8">https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report</a></em></p>
<h2><strong>What if there is the opposite to “broken window theory?”</strong></h2>
<p>I know that “connecting various urban practices across scales” sounds a bit ambitious , so let me break it down a little bit more to show you what we had in mind.</p>
<p>We started from the image of “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0fKBhvDjuy0">*Powers of Ten</a>*” , a film by Charles and Ray Eames. It illustrates the world — from everyday picnics to cosmic mystery and even to the level of a carbon atom — as an arena of continuity. It is a work that travels from the viewpoint of XL to that of XS, and has exponential powers to emphasize the importance of scale.</p>
<p>Another example; the broken windows theory was proposed by James Q. Wilson and George Kelling in 1982. Iit is the theory that uses broken windows as a metaphor/indicator showing disorder and the decay of neighborhoods. If there is one broken window in the town, this will lead to another being broken and another, which ultimately leads to arise in the crime rate of the town as a whole, and finally linking to urban disorder and incivility within a community.</p>
<p>The broken window theory is a negative example, but it certainly highlights the importance of scales — the world as an arena of continuity. What if we can design the opposite phenomenon to the broken window theory by connecting various urban practices to achieve abigger effect?</p>
<p>Below are some of the quotes from the guest speakers on this topic.</p>
<h2><strong>Citizens who use and update their cities — Yukako Ishikawa</strong></h2>
<p>Yukako Ishikawa, a director of Shibuya Hack Project, said that the “broken window theory” has a lot in common with tactical urbanism , which is the approach that this project is taking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Our motivation is to encourage the XS size bottom-up approach by citizens, who are often disconnected by large scale urban development by the administration or private companies. We need a common language to find a familiar arena between the two different scales.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*6nGHIonXubV8o5Oi.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h2><strong>Citizens’ everyday lives (XS) in the urban community — Jun Aoki (Nest.inc)</strong></h2>
<p>Mr. Aoki, a famous landlord in Japan, believes that the smallest unit of our urban space is the residents’ everyday lives and their living space. In Aoki’s rental housings, the residents can make home gardens and organize events by themselves or create shared offices and customize their homes as they want — something that is quite rare in Japan.</p>
<p>He has also devoted himself to revitalizing<a href="https://goo.gl/T6PdXf"> Minami-Ikebukuro Park</a>, which was re-opened in spring 2016 after five years of renovations. This park is now a popular hangout and lunch spot for locals with various activities such as Marche, film screenings, and weddings.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>The place of living should be connected to a community and its surroundings — we can scale up from XS to S by letting people have freedom to use their living space and sort of encroach towards their urban surroundings.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*bVxnUYJ7s7fs4eIo.jpg" alt="https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report"><em><a href="https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report">https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report</a></em></p>
<h2><strong>“Urban management” as a way to connect the various urban scales — Atsumi Hayashi (Tokyo R Real Estate)</strong></h2>
<p>Mr. Hayashi, co-chairman of<a href="https://www.realtokyoestate.co.jp/"> Tokyo R Real Estate</a> and the architecture firm<a href="http://www.speac.co.jp/"> SPEAC</a> argues the importance of applying the concept of management into cities as a way to include the industrial strategies and human resources and other manageable factors to establish a creative place in microscopic thinking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>It is important to have strategies and management skills to concern the large-scaled regional socio-economic sustainability while putting people first and believing in the power of smallness led by the citizens.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*MQwXhTbCz6Q-fI4y.jpg" alt="https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report"><em><a href="https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report">https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report</a></em></p>
<h2>Workshop</h2>
<p>The event also involved fieldwork to the riverside in Shibuya and a subsequent workshop. This served to re-discover regional assets from the viewpoint of individuals and to think about their own public space, namely “personal stalls”.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*eraV2wqT41VeUw9J.jpg" alt="https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report3"><em><a href="https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report3">https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report3</a></em></p>
<p>If you want to know more about the event, check out the event reports (available only in Japanese).</p>
<p>Part1: <a href="https://l.messenger.com/l.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Floftwork.com%2Fjp%2Fevent%2F20180313_hmc_report&amp;h=ATMB4AWkQqiqV6gUJLAJMpUWFMIkYB1JcKAdPhFCdrdxKIaCj31JlPZ4DgYwSoJSOTv8jeAnNRo3MM2KX-oG1Ij5SHuC9c6jVmXL_Pe8f7gxj6HjMcFW_w3hLh8">https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report</a><br>
Part2: <a href="https://l.messenger.com/l.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Floftwork.com%2Fjp%2Fevent%2F20180313_hmc_report2&amp;h=ATMB4AWkQqiqV6gUJLAJMpUWFMIkYB1JcKAdPhFCdrdxKIaCj31JlPZ4DgYwSoJSOTv8jeAnNRo3MM2KX-oG1Ij5SHuC9c6jVmXL_Pe8f7gxj6HjMcFW_w3hLh8">https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report2</a><br>
Part3: <a href="https://l.messenger.com/l.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Floftwork.com%2Fjp%2Fevent%2F20180313_hmc_report3&amp;h=ATMB4AWkQqiqV6gUJLAJMpUWFMIkYB1JcKAdPhFCdrdxKIaCj31JlPZ4DgYwSoJSOTv8jeAnNRo3MM2KX-oG1Ij5SHuC9c6jVmXL_Pe8f7gxj6HjMcFW_w3hLh8">https://loftwork.com/jp/event/20180313_hmc_report3</a></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/4486/1*Ri_Z7ya0Qcb6-2MbhnZvvg.jpeg" alt=""></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.comhttps://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*IEAJ4RS-SlSJcmKu.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ 2 alternative spots to visit in Kuala Lumpur]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/kuala lumpur/alternativespot</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/kuala lumpur/alternativespot</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>Few months ago I found this interesting website <a href="https://alternativeasia.net/">ALTERNATIVE ASIA</a>, which introduces the interesting independent art spaces in the south east Asian countries. Most of these spaces are owned and managed by the artists themselves, and they are using the spacesnot only as galleries, but inviting a wide range of people to have workshops, festivals and symposiums and so on.</p>
<p>I liked the author’s unique eyes, to find the “alternative” — which, in my understanding, challenges the conventional idea of what Asian cities are about and show us the emerging wave of cultural movement created by the locals.</p>
<p>With that in mind, I tried to find the alternative spots in Kuala Lumpur, when I visited there in February 2018. I believe that we all share the same problems of lacking decent public space in our cities, isolation of young creatives due to the rapid urban/economic transformation that is turning our city to the place of consumption. Kuala Lumpur is definitely part of the Karma, that’s why it’s valuable to know what’s there to be against it.</p>
<p>This post is to introduce two alternative spaces you can visit.</p>
<h2>1. Fab Space</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*RWd-sME5koYGLTK8jrDlrA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>I firstly got to know <a href="https://www.fabspacekl.com/">Fab Space</a> through <a href="https://loftwork.com/jp/">Loftwork</a>, a deign hub I used to work in Tokyo. Fab Space is a <strong>creative space</strong> where your ideas can become a tangible reality and innovation and new ideas are birthed.</p>
<p>This is a <strong>digital innovation lab</strong> where you can have access to machines, such as laser cutter, 3d printer, UV printer, latex printer, CNC milling machine, which are not commonly accessible to the public.</p>
<p>Not only that — it focuses on <strong>building a community</strong> of creatives and innovative people to exchange their ideas and create something anew.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*9hJj_tm8rDUo1rejae_TwQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*tx45Dhf9-D_Y_0pZtAg51Q.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*pcBPpiKjIs60SYXdFAx2-g.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*orhDJxVNVFw5wjJ3KawiBA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*7Sg4uX3yg1BrQ73qSlXBIg.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*W_FA-_5BJkbheIY5OlzisA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*_rs9aj7nw4--kdk7KSWd6w.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*IYqKHrCjBGgHskMWq2Pevg.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<h2>2. APW Bangstar</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8064/1*YHrLpMZZX7RGwxXxFv08sg.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>An old printing factory <a href="https://apw.my/">APW Bangstar</a> was renovated to become a creative hub where arts, culture, business and technology converge. Within its big industrial area, APW Bangstar hosts collaborative workspace, F&amp;B outlets, event venues and pocket parks — and everyone is welcome to hangout!</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8064/1*qEdWPoAzBHuk16naXGlSQQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8064/1*gHSUhx9ADrAAVIEDr0y3lA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8064/1*HQjoTFOgUh1HSPGBXSQKMA.jpeg" alt="It has one of the hippest coffee shop in Kuala Lumpur"><em>It has one of the hippest coffee shop in Kuala Lumpur</em></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*gbGryDWsVYi0DaMDkos9Eg.jpeg" alt="Urban farming laboratory"><em>Urban farming laboratory</em></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8064/1*ZiIptR4xAGFdCjYYMd4_EQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/6048/1*cZJuO0oREVtd6esQTA5YOQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8064/1*zen47XcO0SGGxNJn6frcHQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8064/1*3_CuK2D0KbR_HviFYmJ6Eg.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*n3m2Qie1nP3qzblsCdmYYw.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*ZQHdKgE_9Dfg45U9aIlpQg.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*GFd56GPQnplUaEmCQ99rew.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*Mj1XVkftGzOvaeeGjwswDA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*Fcn_u0U2w4bzqRWMpa-mYw.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*NqqKK7fLz5olRbUecbajYA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*U2cJfYMGuPIz7uTAqwtJxA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8064/1*SGVVJn6W4c-iQCBM0Di1ZA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8064/1*PUu9yaxzrJXv1pvU5An4Yg.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8064/1*JYMDFNMAaUEHJWYbvIWGxA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8064/1*8yc53aJghk430SgKdhJqJQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8064/1*BL7klGBu6cBh5Olny7A4HA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/6048/1*4dpG-0cEi9hFENmNx5UxmA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.comhttps://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8000/1*RWd-sME5koYGLTK8jrDlrA.jpeg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Urbanist MeetUp Tokyo: Examining the role of “urbanists” in improving urban life in Tokyo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/urbanistmeetuptokyo</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/urbanistmeetuptokyo</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>Last year, I organized an “Urbanist Meetup Tokyo”, and this post aims to discuss the importance of interdisciplinary collaboration among the people who understand urbanity and love the cities we live in. The term “urbanist” is not popularly used in the Japanese context, but I believe that what Japanese cities (particularly Tokyo) need in this age of rapid transformation is to go beyond “civil engineering” and the idea that the urban environment is the playground of merely architects and planners.</p>
<h2>Urbanist MeetUp Tokyo</h2>
<p>Cities are formed/imagined/lived and used by people from various backgrounds and with interests. The increasingly popular Japanese concept of “machi-zukuri” (community/neighborhood planning — check out this article<a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/0955580022000008745"> here</a>), for instance, means a departure from the traditional form of top-down planning and covers variety of fields, such as community development, renovation, regional branding, town development, real estate, geography, architecture, and more. Yes, there are tons of professions that are closely related to cities, not only architects and planners — so what is the meaning of connecting all these activities and professions on the horizontal axis?</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*KhR9gu4HI_5x8PeRTYHBdw.jpeg" alt=""><br>
<img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*ZAcYtkmVfFvpKeTMaOXRag.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>2017 December in Tokyo; approximately 150 urbanists showed up to the meetup. The meetup was originally initiated by a few young architects from the renovation industry, who have been gathering and holding a party every year for the past 4 years in order to extend the narrow frame of the industry.</p>
<p>Since then, the concept has spread not only among the renovation industry but also to real estate, architectural design, town planning and other areas. This time, we expanded the frame further and gathered a wide variety of people who were related to cities in various ways in order to create a more inviting and strong community — we decided to name it “Urbanist MeetUp”.</p>
<p>In this meetup, the word “urbanist” was widely defined as “people who make/use/live cities”, and we invited 23 urbanists to give a short pitch about their activities — their approach and passion for cities. A small game followed to elicit conversation among participants.</p>
<p>The beauty of this meetup was that there was a variety of professions involved — not only architects and planners, but also people from community development, writers and editors from the media covering a variety of urban issues, and IT engineers who are developing apps about cities. All the speakers and participants were able to meet others who are equally passionate about cities, but had totally different professions and approaches. If that doesn’t trigger a conversation towards brand-new ideas and inspiration, what will?</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*gcwsC6txM0SI0n27IsbWzQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*k8vmwM3oLRZ6Y5fy9l4pZQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<h2>Fireside Chat for cities@Tokyo</h2>
<p>As another example , a few months ago my colleague and I organized a meetup called “Fireside Chat for Cities” . This was a meetup for urbanists to discuss various topics related to cities in an interactive manner. We gathered in a small bar on Shinjuku Golden Street, and the focus was a discussion of the subjective, personal stories of the participants.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/3998/1*is3alF3-N-K-Vh7VAj2JJw.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/3998/1*XGsFsQo0HPG6aGr-53t0gQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>We came up with some random city-related themes such as “noise, crowded trains, staircases, drinking companions, convenience stores, windows, romance, smell, gender” , whereby each participant selected one of the themes and talked about what they had experienced regarding that topic in cities. The aim was to grasp our cities through the complexity of how one experiences and lives in a city and gets to know the others’ different approaches and opinions.</p>
<p>Most of the participants were not architects or urban planners, but when they talked about their subjective memories and experiences of the cities, it really didn’t matter who “knew” the city better.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/3000/1*CtGxKf36qMHkK5R5K4bmGA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/3000/1*tdUbhqoxzQYirPzDuht5fg.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<h2>Who is the “urbanist”?</h2>
<p>In Japan, the word urbanism is often translated in association with urban planning and civil engineering skills, and in many cases it is considered that urbanist = urban planner. However, if the urbanist is grasped broadly as those people who “make” cities and “use/live” cities, we can bring together people from a wide variety of specialized fields, like those gathered in this meetup under the same term — even the citizens.</p>
<p>The term urbanist is also becoming more and more acknowledged.</p>
<p>Scott Bonjukian, a writer in<a href="https://www.theurbanist.org/2016/01/19/why-i-call-myself-an-urbanist/"> The Urbanist,</a> published an article in 2016 called “<a href="https://www.theurbanist.org/2016/01/19/why-i-call-myself-an-urbanist/">Why I call myself an urbanist</a>” in which he said that the English words “urbanism” and “urbanist” have recently become popular. He summaries that “<em>urbanists want more people (of all types) to have equal access to housing variety (apartments, townhouse, backyard cottages, houses, duplexes, etc.), more ways to get around (transit, walking, bicycling, ride-share, vanpool, etc.), more to see and do (parks, cafes, bars, museums, shops, etc.), and to have more grassroots influence on city government.</em>” He defines himself as one of them.</p>
<p>In response to this article, Brandon Donnelly, an architectural blogger and creator, said: *“If you look it up in the dictionary, you’ll likely get something along the lines of: someone who is a specialist in city planning. But I bet that there are many people out there who would self-identity as being an urbanist, but who would also not consider themselves specialists in the field. The term has evolved to imply other things.“ *(Brandon Donnelly,<a href="http://brandondonnelly.com/post/137648883663/what-is-an-urbanist"> What is an urbanist?</a>)</p>
<p>In addition, Christian Dimmer, who teaches urban studies at Waseda University in Tokyo, uses the word “citizen urbanists”, arguing that we citizens as the urban dwellers are the essence of the urbanist.</p>
<h2>Urbanist in Tokyo</h2>
<p>To sum up, I believe that those we call urbanists should not only be the “specialists” who make the physical environment of cities (like architects and city planners) but also other specialists and, most importantly, the citizens , who are participating in the urbanity.</p>
<p>Japan is a country undergoing profound socio-economic and demographic transformation. Tokyo, specifically, is experiencing massive transformation with the very clear goal of hosting the Olympic Games in 2020. Looking at a map of prospective urban development of the whole city, you would be surprised at how many constructions are going on and how <em>similar</em> all these buildings are — all are concrete skyscrapers for fancy offices and hotels.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*18hAqZo_zfRi_y6OPOZrjw.png" alt=""></p>
<p>While some are taking advantage of this economic boom, there have also been some very concerned voices about citizens’ rights to cities and urban commons. Some say that Tokyo is increasingly changing without the citizens’ will — its changes are based on developers’ money games.</p>
<p>(If you want to know more about what’s happening, you can check out such research papers as “<a href="https://www.nri.com/~/media/PDF/global/opinion/papers/2015/np2015200.pdf">The need for rebuilding Tokyo with the 2020 Tokyo Olympics as impetus</a>”.)</p>
<p>I want to see more encouraging stories of people who participate and act in Japanese cities, not just of those who are imagined to be the stakeholders and responsible for making them.</p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.comhttps://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*KhR9gu4HI_5x8PeRTYHBdw.jpeg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Subjective Map Workshop #Shibuya]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/subjectivemapworkshop</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/subjectivemapworkshop</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>In 2017 December, I organized a workshop to encourage people to make their own map based on their own subjective experiences of a city. This article explains the philosophy behind this workshop as well as why and how much map making matters.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/5248/1*aHOJjlyLmGAcIGlTtX3JIA.jpeg" alt=""><br>
<img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2048/1*61dxZGg-UaOyCMia1AIjUw.png" alt=""></p>
<h2>The idea started from this beautiful map</h2>
<p>A few months before the workshop, I traveled to Bangkok, Thailand, for a holiday with some of my best friends. It was my first journey to Thailand and I didn’t have any prior knowledge about the city. For the first few days we visited the major famous temples and markets etc., all the touristic spots for which you can easily find information on Google or in guidebooks. However, I knew that something was missing.</p>
<p>I appreciate local culture and the daily life that is lived and constantly being updated by the people who live there. For me. it is far more meaningful to visit a local community center than to over-spend in an expensive restaurant in a touristic city center.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, Google Maps couldn’t give me what I wanted, even with intensive research. What changed my stay in Bangkok was this beautiful map, which I found by change at a local creative space called<a href="http://www.bangkok.com/magazine/the-jam-factory-bangkok.htm"> the Jam Factory Bangkok</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*3-F6ftwV93Il-X92VEL3pw.jpeg" alt="Image by Nancy Chandler’s Thailand"><em>Image by <a href="http://nancychandler.net/nancychandlersblog.html">Nancy Chandler’s Thailand</a></em></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2812/1*RQO6j2U2r-_RKhTKMS9IHw.jpeg" alt="Image by Nancy Chandler’s Thailand"><em>Image by <a href="http://nancychandler.net/nancychandlersblog.html">Nancy Chandler’s Thailand</a></em></p>
<p>What’s so special about this map, with its excellent hand-drawing, is that it appears very… let’s say “biased” in a good way. Sure, there are some objective facts written on it, such as the names of the temples and so on, but you can really feel the presence of a map maker who has walked through and “felt” specific parts of the city in their own way. It talks about all the seemingly “useless” small things that you never read on Google Maps.</p>
<p>It even reminds me of<a href="https://use-it.travel/home"> USE-It Map Europe</a>, which is an alternative map making movement for young travelers that I can never stop loving.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*0pebAn2aV90Qgx02TNKdAw.png" alt="USE-it Map Europe: https://use-it.travel/home"><em>USE-it Map Europe: <a href="https://use-it.travel/home">https://use-it.travel/home</a></em></p>
<h2>No map is neutral</h2>
<p>Maps tell stories.</p>
<p>We see maps on a daily bases: On our phones, in the stations, in guidebooks etc… to get from point A to B. People tend to think that the maps we see/use every day — especially digital maps like Google Maps — are something very logical and objective. We simply don’t question them. On the other hand, something like Nancy Chandler’s map of Bangkok, which contains personal opinions, feelings, and memories, might be judged as “illogical”.</p>
<p>But is it really so black and white?</p>
<p>In fact, we can’t trust these “logical maps” as a pure “fact” either.</p>
<center><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VhLrEAgeMs4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></center>
<p>This brilliant talk by Monica Stephens teaches us to be more critical about what digital maps (and analogue maps, even though they aren’t mentioned in the talk) are showing us. I won’t summarize her argument here in detail, but her message is clear — our maps are different based on our world view. And we should wonder whose world view and whose perception we are seeing on the maps, and whose perspective has been left out.</p>
<p>For instance, the Mercator projection has famously been criticized for spreading a western-oriented world view, and there is an extreme inequality of the distribution of spatial information/data that covers the Earth’ surface.</p>
<p>This is why <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vow11HYG7HQ">Henk van Houtum</a> in his TED talk powerfully calls for the need to make new maps, to free the map from politics and emancipate it from the dominant world view — and make it our own.</p>
<h2>Subjective Map Workshop</h2>
<p>What if we each had our OWN map, one that didn’t get filtered by Google Maps and someone else’s world view? What if we had maps that talked about the small, local details that are otherwise left out by mainstream map making?</p>
<p>With this motivation, some of my colleagues and I decided to throw a subjective map workshop in different parts of Tokyo — and we chose Shibuya as the first location.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/9216/1*Y5VEWsyb4jqUD-L-nSpexg.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*j-2SLsrfImpoOnShuKhmkA.png" alt="The idea was to collect multiple ideas and combine them together, and to make it sharable with others!"><em>The idea was to collect multiple ideas and combine them together, and to make it sharable with others!</em></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/5248/1*_-DTBn1Rn-Yz0gMlfSaHIg.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>At the beginning, we learned map making techniques and the storytelling power of maps. Afterwards we just simply went out onto the streets for individual fieldwork, and wrote down our personal stories or opinions through own perspectives. For those who didn’t know what to do, I advised them to pay attention to personal memories and any attachments to a specific part of the city as well as sense of belonging, tips to enjoy favorite spots, even smell, sense of security, light and darkness, and so on.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/9216/1*KsTcVBNtuqS1-1lLIGXjMQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/9216/1*oJumCUy_D-wUo3VUr6X64g.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/5248/1*UjejxhR8H7GlttxJ5Hjggw.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/5248/1*aHOJjlyLmGAcIGlTtX3JIA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/3936/1*KmPmDAS_Gv6CNZ7sDYdrzA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/5248/1*ql9zdw-89dY9Ryj1d_Xg0w.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/5248/1*qxQCHCVW_bdPtEAUeYROLQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/5248/1*Z_WiLJ8K6tBT4vIYhJ1uhg.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/5248/1*RlymD5GP9noaz_Wm5gruTA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/5248/1*Gy5b52e0pxKukD_Y-ASMBQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/5248/1*5G7fWTZmHYj_LbljUSE0cg.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/5248/1*ocdUV80pTplvLur7N0Mq0Q.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/3936/1*TfiujDfr6H36n5q321e_QA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<h2>This is the result. And what’s next?</h2>
<p>In the end we had some incredibly fun and creative maps that were directly related to their creators’ personal ways of making sense of the urban surroundings.</p>
<p>This is just one of the examples from the participants. She is someone who always pays attention to trashcans when she walks in Shibuya, and is always trying to discern the personalities of each of them. This highlights the hidden parts of our everyday life, something that is not widely discussed but definitely part of our urban life at an unconscious level.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/6612/1*IBwizLwGxCNvE8m9qa-FDQ.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>I’m in the process of synthesizing all the maps into one single map (this is the tough part…) and it should soon be ready for distribution to involve more people in this subjective map movement. Wouldn’t it be fun to think about a subjective map#Paris or a subjective map#Toronto?</p>
<p>It would be nice to have more critical map lovers who understand and are careful about how much our minds and spatial understanding are influenced by the dominant existing maps and other forms of spatial information.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading!</p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.comhttps://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/5248/1*aHOJjlyLmGAcIGlTtX3JIA.jpeg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Interview: ILLLUTRON, a maker space that moves across the Copenhagen port]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/copenhagen/Interview_Illutron</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/copenhagen/Interview_Illutron</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/copenhagen/Interview_Illutron/med/illutron01.jpg"> <em>Reference: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/illutron/">ILLUTRON facebook</a></em></p>
<p>I manage to have an interview with <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vanessajcarpenter">Vanessa Carpenter</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8DD2EpBXz1o">Nikolaj Dzl Mobius </a>— the co-founders of ILLUTRON, which is a maker space that is anchored at the port in Copenhagen, Denmark. It is a renovated 400-ton old ship and now used as a project space for artists, entrepreneurs, and creators. I decided to ask Vanessa and Nikolaj how they pushed their idea of creating a maker space here in Copenhagen.</p>
<hr>
<p><em><strong>Would you tell me about your background? I heard Vanessa went to Malmo University in Sweden majoring in interactive design. How did you go from there to ILLUTRON?</strong></em></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/copenhagen/Interview_Illutron/med/illutron02.jpg"></p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> I am originally from Canada, at Vancouver University where I majored in interactive art and technology. I was introduced by a classmate who was at Malmo University to do my masters in Sweden and ended up staying there for two years.</p>
<p>The encounter with ILLUTRON is shortly after moving to Sweden. During the firs week of my masters, one of my Danish classmates said to me, “There is an interesting boat in Copenhagen, come and have a look.”</p>
<p>I still remember that day very well. It was very foggy evening. After a party we decided to go have a look at boat on the harbor and I was amazed by the size of the boat.</p>
<p>When I got told a boat I imagined something small, but when I saw I didn’t expect the boat to be so big. It was surrounded by electronic devices, robots and other junk, I feel in love with that mysterious feel straight away.</p>
<p><em><strong>It’s like one scene out of a movie! What sort of boat was it?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> ILLUTRON was once called* a half-machine* and was used to dig cables and wiring when building bridges around Denmark. After fulfilling his role, a friend of us bought the boat that had been neglected for a long time at the port in the Christiania district of Copenhagen. The encounter with the boat that night was the start up and operation of ILLUTRON.</p>
<p><em><strong>Dzl, you are also one of the core members of ILLUTRON, and also FabLab in Roskilde city. Could you tell me about your background?</strong></em></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/copenhagen/Interview_Illutron/med/illutron03.jpg"></p>
<p><strong>Dzl:</strong> I am from Copenhagen and I have always been involved with technology and art. I have created art work myself, taught various skills in the technology.</p>
<p>FabLab, which I am part of, is located on the campus of Roskilde University and puts emphasis on education. Since it is an open space, it isn’t just for students but also for the general public. We teach them how to use various machines such as 3D printers and laser cutters and also run tutorials according to their needs regarding technology in general.</p>
<p>In many Fab Spaces, they are told “You can use 3D printers and laser cutters freely, good luck!,” and they are left to figure it out on their own. But, in FabLab, the staff looks at the materials together and gives advice for their projects so that amateurs can use and understand it easily.</p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> In Copenhagen, there is currently a big movement in terms of technology and art, therefore we put a huge emphasis the educating part.</p>
<h2>ILLUTRON was born from the desire to create “our own place.”</h2>
<p><em><strong>Why did you decide to reconstruct it into a maker space, not anything else?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dzl:</strong> In Denmark, there were several small maker space, mainly in the Christiania district and Vestabro district, and it was the experiment site of various projects. These spaces were scattered in low-priced areas such as closed down industrial areas.</p>
<p>However, in recent years, it was swallowed by the swell of re-development. With the population of Copenhagen increasing dramatically, building offices and apartments were built in in areas that didn’t have many developments.</p>
<p>The artists and creators who gathered ins mall maker space areas had been driven away. It is those who had created new places and have made the area interesting, but they were kicked out as soon as the area became required for re-development. Due to this, artists and creators felt that they needed a their, ‘own place,’ which could never be driven out.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/copenhagen/Interview_Illutron/med/illutron04.jpg"><br>
<em>One of the performances at ILLUTRON.See: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/illutron/">ILLUTRON facebook</a></em></p>
<p><em><strong>It is related to the issue of gentrification in Copenhagen.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dzl:</strong> Yes indeed. That is why it was important that “ILLUTRON can never be kicked out no matter what happens”. For example, the Vestablo district, which was originally a very low rent area, has become a popular spot in recent years for tourists and investors which means artists living there originally have been forced out.</p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong>ILLUTRON floats in the water and can move anywhere so nothing can be kicked out!</p>
<p><strong>Dzl:</strong>That’s why the representatives of the maker space cooperated and gathered funds and bought a ship together. Because it is a used ship, we repaired it together. There are still a few places that have not been repaired yet …. But this boat is ours so no one can take over!</p>
<h2>Involving locals while moving</h2>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/copenhagen/Interview_Illutron/med/illutron05.jpg"></p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> After the repairs of the ship and the official opening of ILLUTRON we have set up various projects such as large scale crafts which many could participate in and a number of small projects.</p>
<p>Is there anything you are particular about while doing these projects?</p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> ILLUTRON is constantly moving from port to port of Copenhagen and we are trying to connect with the community in that area when we do the project. I think a good example is when it was anchored in Sydhavnen.</p>
<p>This area used to be an industrial area, but recently the influx of wealthy families means many new apartments are being built. It was interesting that the residents here were initially distant from us. I think the thought it was a gathering of weird people. Various experiments and work were done in ILLUTRON, and sometimes blow a fire from a ship as part of the performance (laughs), I guess that would make people wary!</p>
<p>We started to think it was hopeless and then we decided to do engineering workshops for kids in the area. By involving kids we were able to get more people involved and families in the area to join the workshops, art events and performances.</p>
<p>It was very pleasant to see the “odd-ballers” who ride around second-hand ships and the wealthy families in this area working on the same project. Currently, instead of Sydhavnen we are anchored at the other ports of Copenhagen, but the way we involve locals has not changed.</p>
<p><em><strong>What does it mean to involve the locals of the area?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dzl:</strong> ILLUTRON is a public space. No matter where it is anchored anyone can come in freely and do whatever they want to do.</p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> We do various activities such as large-scale cultural events named “KulturHavn” (cultural port) and anyone can participate easily. We don’t just do performances, we also hang screens up to show movies and experiments showing robots.</p>
<p><strong>Dzl:</strong> In particular, “access to waterside” is one of the most important topics. The port of Copenhagen is operated by private companies there are actually very few places where people can enjoy the waterside. That is why ILLUTRON often does projects with waterfront as a theme.</p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> There are definitely many projects that use boats or something floating on water. Having a small orchestra on a small boat and go along the port, and in Christmas we do a floating tree.</p>
<p><em><strong>How do you get the staffs and expenses?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> We have 20 main members, but we constantly have new members who bring new ideas to the table. Now the original members are completely hands off and it has be handed down to the younger generations. It has become an autonomous ecosystem.</p>
<p>Usually it is necessary to pay to have your boat on the port but as long as we are doing cultural events we have been told by the Copenhangen city council that we can have out boat on the port for free. We also manage by getting funding for each project and the membership free from the members.</p>
<p><strong>Dzl:</strong> ILLUTRON is a physical space as well as an area for networking It is used by various organizations and individuals who have a range of ideas and skills and it has also become a very active community on SNS.</p>
<h2>If you think of something, give it ago- ‘Do-ocracy’</h2>
<p><em><strong>I’d love to hear your key tips for running a community!</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> For myself I am more of a provider of facility than a creator. For example, ‘Idemo Lab,’ is something we are currently setting up, and by organizing up workshops and events in this space, we create communities and you’re able to support the growth of a range of different people - this is the mission.</p>
<p><strong>Dzl:</strong> That’s right. At events we are setting, it is important that it is not just interactivity but it is also participatory. There is no point to expect that people will just have fun automatically. What we cherish is the participation of the people from the ideas they have brought in and from there news ideas being born.</p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> The mindset of lets give it shot! Is really important. For example, if you think you want to paint the boat pink, rather than discussing whether I should paint it pink you should just paint it pink! I feel there are a lot of people who just say their opinion but don’t really take that into action. So as long as there isn’t anyone strongly against what you want to do, you should take action and whoever paints the boat pink becomes a winner. Actually doing it is the determining factor.</p>
<p><strong>Dzl:</strong> That is ‘Do-ocracy’!</p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> Do-ocracy is a Copenhagen mentality — people tend to just do thing without really asking. In this city, new attempts and interesting events are always being done. This is done because people don’t waste time discussing. Because people are like in Copenhagen this there’re lots of interesting pop up events and initiatives all the time.</p>
<p>So people in Copenhagen not only say their opinions but they also take action. In Japan, there are people complaining about the way people treat the parks but there are very few people that actually take action and do something about it. This is where we should really look up to in terms of people in Copenhagen.</p>
<h2>“Meaningful” experience is important</h2>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/copenhagen/Interview_Illutron/med/illutron06.jpg"><em>One day at Fablab. Reference: <a href="https://typo3.ruc.dk/Uddannelse/Bacheloruddannelser/Humanistisk-Teknologisk-Bacheloruddannelse/FabLab-RUC">FabLab Official HP</a></em></p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> We are also conscious about being, ‘meaningful.’ Since ILLUTRON is a maker space, it deals with technology a lot of the time, but in recent years it tends to be“technology for technology” — this means a type of technology being made where personal experiences are being ignored. This is something we are very conscious about.</p>
<p>I am studying the concept of “Meaningful Smart Product” with IdemoLab of DELTA. For example, you’re wearing a very nice watch today, you must have a lot of feelings towards and memories with that watch. Image that you have 5 more similar smart watches which may be useful. What if you don’t have the same feelings towards those watches? No matter how far technology goes, if something isn’t meaningful between the person and the object, could you say that it is something really good for us?</p>
<p><em><strong>This is a very interesting issue. You can say something similar with the experiences in the city.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dzl:</strong> Personal attachment is important. There are many forward thinking cities that function without any problems, but cities become something special only when there are individual experiences, thoughts and memories that are attached to the city.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/copenhagen/Interview_Illutron/med/illutron07.jpg"><em>An example of “Meaningful” experiene. In their wedding, Mr. Vanessa wore a bouquet with LED lights and a ring with a galvanic skin reaction device. It is a mechanism that allows Vanessa ‘s mood to be sensed by using the current using the current, blue when she feels calm, and when she is unsure the white in the bouquet changes. In this way, we value how to use technology that closely relates to our own experience and feelings. Reference: <a href="http://www.geekphysical.com/coldfeet_readmore.php">http://www.geekphysical.com/coldfeet_readmore.php</a></em></p>
<p><em><strong>From this interview, I really think the people in Copenhagen must have a “meaningful” relationship with their city. I wonder if it is possible to do something similar with all the cities around the world.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dzl:</strong> It is the people who make the city. If the people in the city want to do it, I think it can happen.</p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> No matter how many workshops or events you do, like I mentioned earlier, nothing will happen if you just stand there waiting. This is something we have also experienced, where people come and say, ‘just tell us simply what you’re doing,’ or ‘tell me how to become creative.’ But if there are just people sitting there waiting for something to happen, life won’t be brought to the city.</p>
<p>No matter how much creative opportunities and space you provide, nothing will happen unless there is awareness or responsibility from the people involved. In other words, having a spirit of your own and having the spirit of Do-ocracy is important. I think this can be said not only just for Copenhagen but for cities in Japan like Tokyo.</p>
<p>Great point. Please tell me what are your ambition for the future?</p>
<p><strong>Dzl:</strong> I would like to continue to focus on teaching about technology and manufacturing. I am really inspired by the educational system for creators and artists at MIT’s Fab Academy.</p>
<p><strong>Vanessa:</strong> I want to get away from replying to emails and meetings and try ‘skunk work’. I would like to really focus on a project for about 3 months and from that I think I would be able to see what’s truly important and a vision for the future. I will also continue the research on the “Meaningful Smart Product”</p>
<p><em><strong>We are looking forward to what the future hold for you! Thank you so much for today!</strong></em></p>
<p><em>(※This article was originally posted on <a href="http://layout.net">layout.net</a>. Interview / Text are by myself)</em></p>
<p>ILLUTRON seen from the sky.<br>
See also: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10204161989114027&amp;set=g.19944302536&amp;type=1&amp;theater">Walter Hannemann</a></p>
<p>Official website: <a href="http://www.illutron.dk/">www.illutron.dk</a><br>
Facebook: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/illutron/">https://www.facebook.com/illutron/</a>Flicker: <a href="https://www.flickr.com/search/?w=all&amp;q=illutron&amp;m=text">https://www.flickr.com/search/?w=all&amp;q=illutron&amp;m=text</a></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/copenhagen/Interview_Illutron/med/illutron01.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Design sprints for sustainable development goals: a recap from Global Goals Jam 2017 #Tokyo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/globalgoalsjam17</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/globalgoalsjam17</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*K1mn1ASdXth8VQYs1zMJ_w.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>On 16th-17th September 2017, I had the honor of hosting the first edition of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/globalgoalsjam">#GlobalGoalsJam</a> in Tokyo at 100BANCH. Global Goals Jam #Tokyo was a two-day event with short design sprints, using the methods from <a href="http://medialabamsterdam.com/">MediaLAB Amsterdam</a> — we invited various professionals, designers, creators, and students from more than 10 countries to share and develop our ideas.</p>
<p>During the <a href="http://www.undp.org/content/undp/en/home/blog/2015/9/16/Around-the-world-the-Social-Good-Summit-celebrates-the-Global-Goals-.html">2015 Social Good Summit</a>, 193 world leaders committed to achieving <a href="http://www.globalgoals.org/">17 Sustainable Development Goals</a> by the year 2030. As an initiative of the United Nations Development Program and MediaLAB Amsterdam, the Global Goals Jam began to design realistic, actionable interventions for these goals. Right now, there are more than 30 cities from different parts of the world supporting the initiatives from the local action.</p>
<iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/243070829" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>I met the co-founders Marco Van Hout and Gijs Gootjes when they came to Tokyo, and I had the honor of receiving an official invitation to be a local host for this incredible global event. This article invites you to get a glimpse at the first edition of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/globalgoalsjam">Global Goals Jam</a> #Tokyo.</p>
<h2><strong>It’s actually very rare in Tokyo to have an event entirely in English, with people from various backgrounds.</strong></h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/9794/1*_VGXsJBMAxLeDXTPksZrnw.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>One thing I wanted to make happen was to make the event truly international and diverse. That means: it should welcome anyone regardless of their age, nationality, gender…. And it should be held in English.</p>
<p>Tokyo is a big, global metropolis and — well, if you know OTHER big metropolises like New York and London, you might be surprised to know that the proportion of foreigners in Tokyo is surprisingly low. Thus, everyday contact with people from different cultural backgrounds is still a rare experience for most Japanese, especially for those who don’t feel comfortable speaking in English. In Global Goals Jam #Tokyo, I was pleased to see people from Japan, Canada, the USA, Mozambique, Tanzania, Madagascar, Mauritius, etc. One of the participants from Mauritius told me that she has been looking for this kind of event in Tokyo for a long time.</p>
<p>It doesn’t matter how well you speak English. What matters is working with someone from a different cultural background and exchanging opinions in a common language towards the same goal. Believe me, I know it can sometimes be very awkward and frustrating. But it’s worth it.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/9794/1*OIjCrTzgzwT96UH01dmVHw.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/9794/1*2omWP-koPhB6NM2rT6deVA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/9794/1*YhsufNauOkWwEpO1gnHoKg.jpeg" alt="David Willoughby from Workers University joined the event as one of the facilitators"><em>David Willoughby from <a href="http://www.workers-u.com/">Workers University</a> joined the event as one of the facilitators</em></p>
<h2><strong>We learned the Design Sprints method from Amsterdam Media Lab.</strong></h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/9794/1*tTl02fXIjQuZD0e5-7OrwQ.jpeg" alt="**Sprint #1 Organize it, experience it / Sprint #2 Respond to it**This was about identifying problems and organizing our ideas">***Sprint #1 Organize it, experience it / Sprint #2 Respond to it<br>
*<em>This was about identifying problems and organizing our ideas</em></p>
<p>Have you ever wondered what the heck a “design methodology” is? I know that it’s a fashionable thing to talk about “design” nowadays, but I always thought that many people didn’t really understand what it was, but just kinda wanted to talk bullshit about it.</p>
<p>That’s why it was very valuable to use the concrete methods established by Amsterdam Media Lab. While leaving out the very fine details that actually fit into the local contexts, Amsterdam Media Lab provides a common language of design methods for the design field (they call it a mission to fight “design waste”), which is open and accessible and where even the beginners can dive straight in.</p>
<p>Check out this <a href="https://medialabamsterdam.com/toolkit/">toolkit</a> — it has all the tools we can use, explaining each step that needs to be followed. It, of course, explains things like the process and for which purpose, how long it takes to complete a work, and so on.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/9794/1*VwEDnJabc9MuNaX-68v8Bg.jpeg" alt="Day 2: Build it and test it"><em><strong>Day 2: Build it and test it</strong></em></p>
<p>The second day was all about developing prototypes. We first made concept sketches to represent our ideas in order to get feedback from the other teams. Afterward, we tried to bring the team’s idea to the physical world for a demonstration. The proto-tools were provided by <a href="https://www.fabcafe.com/">Fabcafe</a> — a fabulous cafe in Tokyo where you can enjoy all the fabrication tools!</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/9794/1*MqtFzL6Bj65Y2DDfVJHKug.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/9794/1*UJNUGR3GebgG24Egk8Uc7w.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<h2><strong>Think BIG, start SMALL, act FAST! Can’t you do the same, Tokyo?</strong></h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/9794/1*NpP_jpQIIzZx6Am8QAXuZA.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>In the final presentations, we delivered various ideas, which were demonstrated as paper or cardboard prototypes, hand-made prototypes made with a laser cutter, video prototyping, and storyboards. Below are some of the prototypes we developed during the event.</p>
<p><strong>Team 1. 「Midori no Heroes」: Goal # 4 Quality Education</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*13H2_EEMvhG8RCWh1N2fsA.png" alt="『Midori no Heroes』Storyboard"><em>『Midori no Heroes』Storyboard</em></p>
<p>Challenge: How to provide vocational education to encourage small farmers in Africa by sending them useful information via feature phones and smartphone?</p>
<p>Their idea:“Midori no Heroes”, as a social entrepreneur, will partner with local research institutes, such as universities, central government and local government, to gather appropriate information for the farmers to farm better and more efficiently and then offer it to local small farmers. The team assumes that basic information such as weather forecasting can be useful since most of the farmers work without planning. The information will be delivered and implemented in two ways, one is via a feature phone for each farmer and the other is via a smartphone at a community center or community church. Midori no Heroes will have workshops at those central places where people regularly get together in order to learn how to use the smartphones and the information and how to implement it in their farming.</p>
<p><strong>Team 2.「Plan B: Shared eco-bags」: Goal # 11 Sustainable Cities and Communities</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*F7gVdhprz_djVJN_jTDnUQ.png" alt="『Shared eco-bags』Video prototype"><em>『Shared eco-bags』Video prototype</em></p>
<p>Challenge: 「Tackling the problem of shoppers consuming an excessive and unnecessary number of plastic bags at grocery stores and convenience stores in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Their idea：In Japan, 305 million plastic bags are used every year (300 bags/year for each person). Plastic bags take more than 1,000 years to decompose. Plan B is a reusable eco-bag that enables people to share / get benefit by using them.</p>
<p><strong>Team 3. 「DiverCity」：Goal # 4 Quality Education</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*Cx2-CIN1pMzQRtbD5TtX3Q.png" alt="『DiverCity』website prototype： https://xd.adobe.com/view/7f7fb204-c645-4a24-99d8-d5487fe76871/"><em>『DiverCity』website prototype： <a href="https://xd.adobe.com/view/7f7fb204-c645-4a24-99d8-d5487fe76871/">https://xd.adobe.com/view/7f7fb204-c645-4a24-99d8-d5487fe76871/</a></em></p>
<p>Challenge: How can we design a solution that promotes respect for diversity and individual differences in Japanese schools?</p>
<p>Their idea：DiverCity is a network of local people who have important life lessons they want to teach. Choosing a career, going your own way, learning from your mistakes, and finding your true self. <em>Tayoubi</em> means “diversity day” in Japanese. We encourage schools to set a specific day or time to think about diversity issues. They can make use of our “Diversity Bank” of local residents with interesting stories to tell. We also provide a “Diversity Pack” of lesson ideas and discussion topics for teachers introducing diversity education to their classrooms. Teachers and schools are free to decide how they implement Tayoubi, according to their available time and other resources.</p>
<p><strong>Team 4. 「Sea You Soon」：Goal # 11 Sustainable Cities and Communities</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*lVZc5xZXqvGMC5kn_jFbKg.png" alt="『SEA you soon』Mockup for an app service"><em>『SEA you soon』Mockup for an app service</em></p>
<p>Challenge: How can we design a solution that turns Tokyo’s water resources into recreational community-building spaces while promoting awareness of the importance of water in our lives?</p>
<p>Their idea：We provide easy access to coastal journeys with experienced fishermen through an app called “SEA you soon’’. One can experience catching fish and eating and cooking them with the locals. The aim is to give people an attachment to the coastal environment for a more sustainable waterfront development.</p>
<p><strong>Team 5. 「Smart Mirror Companion」：Goal # 3 Good Health and Well-Being</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*t5uL6jiHebslCy3XgXiCsQ.png" alt="『Smart Mirror Companion』Video prototype"><em>『Smart Mirror Companion』Video prototype</em></p>
<p>Challenge: Combating the world’s health problems by focusing on well-being and making sure everyone has the tools and resources to be healthy.</p>
<p>Their idea：A mirror powered by a digital personal assistant (like Siri) to be your partner when you need 1) medical assistance 2) or just a companion to be there for you.</p>
<p>Aren’t these ideas great and inspiring? I know that these are not PERFECT perfect — because they were done only in 2 days — but it is surely the beginning of something exciting. Marco, the co-founder of Global Goals Jam, told me that it’s all about “Think BIG, start SMALL, act FAST!”, and I think it could not be phrased any better.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/10368/1*cEMHeNs2OYedBQ-hwQrffg.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>As a person who ALWAYS thinks of things in the context of cities and urbanism, I can’t help but think how valuable it would be to use this structure for the re-development of Tokyo. At the moment, everything seems to be “Think SMALL, start BIG, act SLOW!”. I’d love to apply the design sprint method we’ve learned during the Global Goals Jam to some of the critical urban problems we are facing, such as a shortage of childcare facilities, a lack of safe bicycle infrastructure, an unaffordable housing market, and energy shortages, just to name a few.</p>
<p>I hope you can also come and join us for this year’s Global Goals Jam 2018 #Tokyo!</p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.comhttps://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*K1mn1ASdXth8VQYs1zMJ_w.jpeg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Interview — Christian Dimmer, Urban Studies Prof of Waseda University]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/Interview ChristianDimmer</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/tokyo/Interview ChristianDimmer</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p>I had a great opportunity to interview Christian Dimmer, a space / environment designer who is teaching Urbanism at Waseda University. He has been living in Tokyo for over 15 years to understand Japanese Urbanism, and involving himself in a range of different projects.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*Y41HHAW-LzUp2QoP.jpg" alt="In Dima’s office at Waseda University. On the book shelves there were many books on cities, maps and plans."><em>In Dima’s office at Waseda University. On the book shelves there were many books on cities, maps and plans.</em></p>
<hr>
<p><em><strong>Thank you very much for your time. First of all, please introduce yourself and what you’re currently doing.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dimmer:</strong> Using Japan as a base, I have taught at the University of Tokyo and Waseda University for the past 15 years. As space and environment designer, we conduct research on Urban Studies with the theme of public space and city movement. Until recently, I had been mainly involved with the academic side, but since the Tohoku Earthquake in March 2011 a big opportunity came along for me to get involved to understand the changes in society. I‘ve been involved in Tokyo-based architectural office <a href="http://frontofficetokyo.com/">Frontoffice Tokyo</a>, and <a href="http://mincoco.tasukeaijapan.jp/?p=15354">Tohoku Planning Forum</a>, a project run by an international organization Architecture For Humanity.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*M7qNrSAECDhwoUBy.png" alt="On the “Tohoku Planning Forum” website, you can check detailed information on who is doing what on the restoration in the Tohoku region using an interactive map."><em>On the “Tohoku Planning Forum” website, you can check detailed information on who is doing what on the restoration in the Tohoku region using an interactive map.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Please tell me more about the events after the earthquake.What’s the goal of Tohoku Planning Forum?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dimmer:</strong> As a designer, architect, urban planning expert, citizen mediator, facilitator, we’ve been coming up with ideas for forums and events. This has allowed the local citizens and specialists to discuss the restorations plans.</p>
<p>Architects are familiar with their areas, but it often ends there. City planners, engineers and artists are also the same — they communicate amongst themselves and not with other specialists.</p>
<p>Also there is still hierarchy in the field of city planning and architecture. Even if you do a talk event, people will say, “Oh, that great teacher will come.” When organizing these events I was very conscious about removing the hierarchy and letting anyone speak their opinion.</p>
<p>By doing so, I think that will increase the number of, ‘Citizen Urbanist’.</p>
<p>I am also currently planning on an art project using containers. The idea is to have a moveable exhibition that can go around the Tohoku region, but I’ll talk about this later on.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*ArlbwVF1kD36DvuQ.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h2>Urbanism is not boring.</h2>
<p><em><strong>You used the word facilitator to explain about your work. As a facilitator, it is important to involve a range of people from new and different industries.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dimmer:</strong> That’s right, I think “translation”is what connects people.</p>
<p><em><strong>Could you explain more what you mean by translation?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dimmer:</strong> As an example, I often think of “translating city planning”. The material of the urban master plans in Japan look very boring and very hard to understand. If you have a network with creators, I think that you can “translate” these boring plans into more attractive things while creating a relationship between the specialists and the artists to get citizens involved a plan that is, ‘readable’ and ‘understandable’.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*X4XQhsvSox2G0OKn.jpg" alt="I was able to look at Dima’s planning of Shibuya that was published in 1996, it was easy to read even for non-specialists and the mapping was very attractive. Dima said, he was able to do this easily a long time ago but that skill seemed to disappear over time."><em>I was able to look at Dima’s planning of Shibuya that was published in 1996, it was easy to read even for non-specialists and the mapping was very attractive. Dima said, he was able to do this easily a long time ago but that skill seemed to disappear over time.</em></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*ZhcEI6jkADLfHI1D.jpg" alt="In addition to bird’s-eye views, the booklet also refers to urban dwellers in the area."><em>In addition to bird’s-eye views, the booklet also refers to urban dwellers in the area.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>I see. I was very satisfied with the word “translation” in the context of the city. There are a number of projects that connect the specialists and citizens, and one of my favorite one is called <a href="http://shibuyahack.com/">Shibuya Hack Project</a>. It focuses on connecting people from a range of different areas and local stake holders.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dimmer:</strong> This is a very important activity. We did something similar at <a href="http://place-making.org/projects/tokyo-transitions">Tokyo Transitions</a> in 2015. I feel these activities will increase the number of Citizen Urbanist.</p>
<h2><strong>A focus on connecting person to person — Transition Design</strong></h2>
<p><em><strong>Would you please tell me a little more about ‘Tokyo Transitions?’ Was your main focus on connecting person to person?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dimmer:</strong> Transition Design is a new area, recently Carnegie Mellon University in Pittsburgh has made a program using this name. The climate is changing and the politics are unstable, I feel we are living in a period of ‘transition.’ In South East Asia and Africa a Neoliberal market is taking over the local markets and the refugees are crossing the Mediterranean. In this day of age, are the specialists and policymakers who don’t pay attention to these transitions allowed to make decisions on these grand designs?</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*OPu9leduQqdgG5oV.png" alt="Tokyo transition (Spring 2015) was a week-long project aimed at everyone who lived in the city. The aim was to portray what the city planners, facilitators and community were doing. ‘place/making’ photo by Egami Kenichiro."><em>Tokyo transition (Spring 2015) was a week-long project aimed at everyone who lived in the city. The aim was to portray what the city planners, facilitators and community were doing. ‘place/making’ photo by Egami Kenichiro.</em></p>
<p>Based on ‘transition design,’ last year we recruited people domestically and undergoing the program, ‘Tokyo transitions.’ We walked around the city did talk about events and workshops for a week inviting artists and administrators and not just specialists. A day may look like, discussions at midday based on a particular theme at the talk event and then walk around Minami-Senju and Muko island. It is similar to what the secret club did for the ‘Shibuya Hack Project,’ but for this project, we used the secret messages to help us communicate with the locals and see the hidden spots we’ve missed in the area. From the information gathered we were able to create a mapping, do an exhibition and was able to do a big discussion.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*32x5RHxYb8H0Nhgp.png" alt="For Tokyo Transitions, we will be doing city walking, mapping, forums and three exhibitions. The people involved won’t be just specialists by local artists and administrators. ‘Place/making,’ photo by Egami Kennichiro."><em>For Tokyo Transitions, we will be doing city walking, mapping, forums and three exhibitions. The people involved won’t be just specialists by local artists and administrators. ‘Place/making,’ photo by Egami Kennichiro.</em></p>
<p>The era when small experts make cities is over. Economists, psychologists, graphic designers, and citizens should collaborate with architects and planners to think of a design. The difficult part is specialists prefer specialists and they are creating a wall in their region to protect themselves.</p>
<p><em><strong>That’s right. Many of the events can not be explained by just one particular field. You talked about facilitation, for an event like Tokyo Transitions the key seems to be creating connection across a range of fields.</strong></em></p>
<h2>Working towards the three ‘translations’</h2>
<p><strong>Dimmer:</strong> The way we are going to connect person to person is going to depend on who we connect with who. Therefore what I think is going to be important is a translator. A translator is going to be the key to this concept and there are 3 reasons why.</p>
<p>First, like I’ve said, <strong>the bridge between specialists such as architects and city planners is going to be translators.</strong> Usually we don’t really think about it architects are architectures, geographers are maps, businesses are businesses, I think specialists keep to themselves in their own area of expertise. What we need is current of age is interdisciplinary, a flexible collaboration between different specialists.</p>
<p>Second, <strong>translating among languages and cultures.</strong> Obviously it is important to overcome the difference in language but especially in Japan where the ‘top’ city planners, architects or developers are waiting for an answer from the West. Without ignoring it, instead of just copying and pasting the example of the West, I think it is important to combine the flexible application with the Japanese context.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*VW3Rx9CNqMSry7Kz.jpg" alt="Through translation he is trying to connect regional actors, and facilitating the importance of networking."><em>Through translation he is trying to connect regional actors, and facilitating the importance of networking.</em></p>
<p>The third is <strong>a bridge between translation of the citizen’s community and specialists.</strong> Using difficult languages, designs and maps is a way of losing the locals, in order to increase Urbanist citizens is simplify and make the design and arts created by specialists accessible, this is something loft work is good at.</p>
<h2>”New Urban Commons”</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*OUSn4fspTxny2TbH.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p><em><strong>I understand the concept of translation, it is truly something embodied by Tokyo Transitions.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dimmer:</strong> That’s right. On the last day of Tokyo Transition, Mr. Terai from <a href="https://madcity.jp/">Mad City</a> and Mr. Itou from <a href="http://www.shibaurahouse.jp/">Shibaura House</a> did the talks. Listening to the involvement of these people really gets me motivated. Telling people what to do, or this is the right way will not motivate people to take action. instead, listening to success stories I feel will create more of an impact.</p>
<p>For example, Mr. Ito of Shibaura House, he was the one that changed a typical advertisement company into something new, and I think his road to success was full of failures, trial and errors. I think the story told by Mr.Ito will reach out to people at a personal level, be encouraging and an inspiration.</p>
<p><em><strong>I’ve also read your paper on ‘new urban commons’. Could you explain a bit more about it?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dimmer</strong> There is a concept called “commons”. It is a shared resource that everyone can access, and many discussions are done in social relations. In Japanese it is translated as iriai, but what I’m interested in the new area is, ‘new urban commons.’ For example, Shibaura House or where I’m living (<a href="http://www.collectivehouse.co.jp/">Kankan forest</a>) there are new communities around.</p>
<p>What is distinctive about such urban new commons is that it is more open, unlike the traditional old closed community. It is necessary practice amongst new people coming and going. Shibaura House and Kankan forest communities are constantly evolving and performing, this won’t end and there is not final picture.</p>
<p><em><strong>&quot;Practice&quot; is a perfect word to describe the commons, I think.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dimmer:</strong> Yes it is. Commons and communities wasn’t statically built. It was practiced, the point that is changes may be a better verb. The important part is updating inner community, values and rules and continuously being new and dynamic. If this flow ends then the commons will die out.</p>
<p><em><strong>Based on what we talked about what do you think is important for the cities in Japan? You being post growth society and doing lectures on building a place post Tohoku Earth quake.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Dimmer:</strong> I think we are heading toward a positive direction in terms of, ‘new urban commons,’ from new places being born like Shibaura House and Kankan forest. I am looking forward to the increasing strength of urban life, consideration towards the environment, DIY and share mentality in Japan which will create, new urban commons. However as stated, common is a living thing, through communication and workshops I feel we will need to continue these collaborative activities.</p>
<p><em><strong>Thank you so much for sharing your ideas today!</strong></em></p>
<p>Christian Dimmer<br>
Assistant professor of the international education department at Waseda University/ Space and Environment designer, urban researcher.</p>
<p><em>(※This article was originally posted on <a href="http://layout.net/">layout.net</a>. Interview / Text are by myself)</em></p>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.comhttps://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*Y41HHAW-LzUp2QoP.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Urbanism-Related Things to do and read @Vienna]]></title>
            <link>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vienna/Introduction</link>
            <guid>https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/vienna/Introduction</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
<p><img alt="" src="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vienna/Introduction/med/jacek-dylag-579742-unsplash.jpg"></p>
<h3>Things to do, places to go</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>An art &amp; cultural center in the bread factory — <a href="http://www.brotfabrik.wien/en/home.html">Brotfabrik</a>. Perfect example for an adaptive reuse without being too touristic.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.daspackhaus.at/">Das Packhaus</a>: The temporary use project and Vienna’s largest startup hub.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Between 1918 and 1934, Vienna was ruled by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_Democratic_Party_of_Austria">Social Democrats</a> government and they launched an extraordinary campaign to provide housing for working-class residents. Visit <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2015/apr/27/vienna-karl-marx-hof-architecture-politics-ideology-history-cities-50-buildings">Karl Marx Hof</a> and <a href="http://dasrotewien-waschsalon.at/startseite/">The museum in the laundry room</a>!</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3>Read</h3>
<ol start="4">
<li>
<p>Get to know Vienna by reading the short novels and let your imagination wonder— <a href="https://global.oup.com/academic/product/vienna-tales-9780199669790?cc=us&amp;lang=en&amp;">Vienna tales</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>More about Red Vienna: <a href="https://www.virtualvienna.net/the-city-its-people/history-vienna/red-vienna/">RED VIENNA: A WORKER’S PARADISE</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2>Organization</h2>
<ol start="6">
<li>
<p><a href="http://spaceandplace.at/">Space and Place</a> — a non-profit group which uses social interventions to make important new connections across the city</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.paradocks.at/">Paradocks / Das Packhaus</a> is a project to connect vacant spaces and city’s demands by finding creative potential in them. Paradocks stands for the “paradox” of demand and supply of space in a city.</p>
</li>
</ol>
]]></description>
            <enclosure url="https://www.travelingcircusofurbanism.com/posts/vienna/Introduction/med/jacek-dylag-579742-unsplash.jpg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>